Okay so congratulations on completing the course. Seriously well done.
And I know if you've followed the course from start to finish you'll be well and truly down with AWS VPCs.
And if this stuff was all new to you when you started the course, then man I am properly chuffed for you,
that means I'm pleased for you. Sometimes I forget not everybody understands the phrases and things I use.
Anyway, AWS and cloud computing in general, it's the future, right.
And this stuff that we've learned, honestly it's going to position you so well for the future of IT.
I'm super excited for you. Also, right, a massive thanks for watching the course.
Now I know I've said this in the previous module, right, but I really do put a huge amount of effort and time
and energy into making these courses, so I genuinely am made up when you guys watch them, like them, and learn
from them. You know what? My kids would like to personally thank you for putting food on the table
at Shay Poulton. But you know what? As much as I am actually certain that I've created a great course
for you here, and don't take that the wrong way, right, but I really, really want your feedback,
good and bad. You know what? If you want the next course that I do to be better than this one,
then I need you to tell me how I can do things better. So do me a favor please and leave comments
on the courses discussion board on Pluralsight.com and ping me on Twitter and the likes.
I do try and answer all questions and I really do appreciate all feedback.
Anyway, what next for you? Well on the topic of AWS, we've already got a bunch of stuff on Pluralsight,
just whack AWS into the search bar and you won't go wrong. But in particular, right, one course that I'm
fairly excited about is called
AWS Certified Sysops Admin Associate or it will be when it's released, right, and it's by Elias Khnaser
who's one my favorite video trainers and he's a really great guy.
Anyway, this course is actually partway through production right now, so by the time you're watching this
it might well be out, but if it's not, keep an eye out for it, right, because it's not going to be far away.
I mean, it covers a bunch of what's covered in this course, and you know what?
I always think that that's good, like a second opinion or the same subject, right, but delivered in a different way
and by a different person. It's quite often a good way to solidify what you're learning.
But the Sysops Admin course here covers a bit more stuff than just the VPC stuff that we've covered,
so a broader range of AWS material. But I'd say, right, the VPC related stuff, it covers it in slightly less
detail than we've done in this course, but I really think the two courses compliment each other.
Anyway, that's me just trying to look out for you there by suggesting another great course.
But don't forget, right,
Pluralsight is building what promises to be probably the most comprehensive library of top quality
AWS training videos with more being released all the time, so keep your eyes peeling.
Now one last shameful personal plug, but if you like AWS, right, then if you're not already into it
I reckon you're going to love Docker.
And well, as it happens, you'd think I planned this, but I've got a cracking course on Docker that I think you'd love.
But don't put off by the title, right, if you're a proper Docker newbie, it is a proper soup to nuts course
on the core Docker engine. So it takes you from zero to, well not quite hero, but well competent with Docker.
And that can only be a good thing for your career as well. And I'm also talking to the guys at Pluralsight
about potentially doing more Docker courses. Now, we never promise anything, right, so just so that we don't
let you down if anything goes wrong, but keep your eyes peeled, there's tons of great stuff in the pipelines
and you know what? Yeah, that's probably all.
Thanks again and congrats again. Now go and rock it with Amazon Web Services.