Ok, bem-vindos a este curso sobre AWS VPC Operations. Obrigado por escolher o curso e posso dizer, um especial
bem-vindo de volta para quem tomou qualquer um dos meus cursos anteriores e está voltando para mais.
Sinceramente, aprecio o seu apoio. Agora então, oh sim,
Amazon Web Services. Quero dizer, sem dúvida, uma das plataformas de tecnologias mais legais e mais importantes
no mundo, como sempre. Quero dizer, é mágico, tão maciçamente legal, mas literalmente moldando o futuro do mundo de TI.
E dentro da AWS, nuvens privadas virtuais estão lá no centro.
They're a proper foundational building block, I'd say right. If you want to be any good at AWS, you have got to
know VPCs and I love them, right. I mean, using AWS and VPCs you can literally build yourself your own
world class data center for virtual machines in the cloud and it's so flippin' easy and cheap.
So just to set some expectations, right, we're going to go from literally nothing
like a blank canvas, right, so no previous experience with AWS is needed, and we're going to go all the way
through building a work VPC, like that data center in the cloud I just mentioned.
So we'll build multiple networks or subnets in different locations for high availability, we'll configure
high speed, highly available internet access, and we'll build load balancers and VPN connections, and all
that kind of stuff, right. And while we're doing it, we'll play around with virtual machines and we'll
share some simple web servers to help round out the demos in the labs that we do.
Oh, and we'll secure it alright with some fundamental security technologies that Amazon provides for us.
And you know what? It's going to be something like, I don't know, 3, 4, 5 hour course, we'll see,
but the point being, in the space of like less than a handful of hours we're going to build a full on working
secured data center of sorts, right, in the cloud. So highly available, high performance, running virtual machines.
And like I said, literally for pennies. And you know what? I'm like still amazed by that because when I cut
my teeth in IT, that kind of thing took months or years and it cost an arm and a leg.
So I'm really excited to be teaching this course and I'm really excited for you.
I think it's going to be the bizzo, an awesome course about an awesome technology, perfect combination.
Okay now then, a quick bit about me before we rock and roll with the course.