Okay then, so in this module we're going to rock and roll with VPNs, virtual private networks.
But right off the bat, I want to take a sec to define a VPN and then outline how we're going to tackle things.
So a VPN, okay, it's an acronym for virtual private network. And back in the day, right, so like when I was
resetting passwords, changing backup tapes, and you know what, pretty much making coffees for my superiors,
technical superiors yeah, well back then, VPNs were nasty things.
I mean, I shutter just thinking about them. So the idea was, when people weren't in the office,
but maybe needed access to company services, I don't know like email or maybe a database or whatever,
well we needed a way to give them a connection from wherever they were back to the office and that connection
had to be secure. So it was a bit like this, right? Well in fact, actually when I graduated into being trusted
enough to be on the IT support on-call router it was exactly like this.
So I don't know what it was, it was like once every 4 or 5 weeks I'd be anointed with the possession of the
on-call mobile phone and a laptop, the likes of which would be almost unrecognizable these days,
a proper honking piece of plastic, but you know what? Doubled as a pretty good weight for dead lifting.
But it had a build in modem and then, right, whenever there was a problem with any of the company's server
infrastructure outside of office hours, I'd fire up the laptop, then obviously I'd wait 5 minutes for it to boot,
then I'd dial back to the office where we had a good old Nortel Contivity VPN concentrator.
Now then, this combination of the laptop with the Nortel VPN Client, the internet, and let's just call
it a VPN router here, this combo let us create what's called an encrypted tunnel from my laptop all the way
through the internet to the corporate network, basically a secure, shall we call it, virtual private network.
And while it was good in theory, right, in practice probably due to like the 56K modem speeds and the likes,
it was a pig, seriously, it was absolutely pants. Now I don't want to waffle okay, so story time is over,
but the principle is this, VPNs are all about tunneling a secure connection over the internet from one point
to another. And back then when I was cutting my teeth in IT, it was from a laptop back to the office.
Now these days, right, fast forward like, I don't know, 20 years or whatever and VPNs are a boatload more
than just that. In fact, what we're going to be talking about in this module, while it's kind of like
what I just talked about, it's different too. So we're going to be talking about hooking up
two locations via the internet, so maybe a corporate office or an existing corporate data center,
and hooking it up back to AWS via the internet using a VPN. And we're going to be configuring, right,
what is an always up VPN, not like me on the on-call laptop, right, where I only fired it up like, I don't know
what it was, maybe once a week or so when something information office broke.
No, what we're going to be doing here is a totally different beast, an always up, reliable VPN connection.
Anyway, okay, hopefully that does us like 1000 foot view primer on VPNs.
Now how we're going to go about this is pretty much like this.
We'll do a little bit more high level stuff, okay. Then we'll outline the major components that make up
an AWS VPN. After that, we'll lash one up. Then we'll talk about something called direct connect,
it's like a VPN, but it's also not like one. More of a full blown leased line DWDM type uber connection
into AWS. I know, it probably makes no sense explained like that, but no sweat, right, on my honor
I'll give it the full treatment later in the module. That's good for now though.
Let's crack on.