So, here we go, right, a Q&A session, though totally rigged. I mean, I've not only written the questions,
and I totally get to edit my own answers so that I'll look great or I guess sound great.
But seriously, I've not done this in any of my courses before, so it could be a totally rubbish idea
and I could end up sounding ridiculous, but I don't know, I was pretty stoked with the idea when I first had it
and in my head at least, I thought it would be great. I thought you'd really like it as viewers.
So you know what? Here's my Twitter handle.
If anybody does actually bother to watch this module, do me a favor, right, and let me know what you thought of it
because seriously, I mean, it's not like a sub-story or anything, but I do put a ton of effort into these courses
and I'd really like to know what works and what doesn't. So here it goes.
I'm a bit nervous actually. First question, so what's the biggest or most common mistake you see people making
with AWS VPCs? Oh, cool. Nice easy one to start off with. Thanks for that.
Yeah, this is a bit weird. Anyway, seriously right. I reckon it's VPC CIDR blocks, so choosing the
IP address space to use in your VPC. If you've watched the course we use the 10.0.0.0/16 network
and I feel like I blabbered on about this quite a lot in the course.
But network planning it's just huge and it's so easy not to bother with or to get wrong.
Probably because it's one of the first things that you do when creating your VPC.
But seriously, get those CIDR blocks wrong and you can find yourself in a deep hole with no ladder to help you out,
you really, really, really want to make sure you're not using the same network addresses in your VPC
that you've already got in use somewhere else on your corporate network.
So for instance, if you're going to go with a 10.0 network for your VPC, make absolutely sure that it's not
the network you're already using in the office or your on-prem data center or anything.
And if you're at a company with a dedicated network team or multiple network teams, you're definitely
going to want to talk to them about this kind of thing. Get them involved and get them on your side
from the start because in IT infrastructure, right, in my experience, the network is where most of
the complexity is. I mean, did you ever wonder why just about every outage is blamed on the network?
Yeah, I know a bunch of the time we use the term network issue or network incident when it's not really
the network, but in all of my years of infrastructure experience, more often than not it is the network.
And I'm not slamming networks or network people here, right? The reason it's usually the network
at the core of the problem is because networking is so freaking complex.
So get in early with your network team and plan out your subnets and stuff with those guys before you start
tearing into your VPC. And as well, don't let the network guys fob you off because your VPC networks
are out there in the cloud and not yet considered part of your network proper.
Treat your VPC networks just like any other corporate network, at least from a planning and an address space
perspective, because I can almost guarantee that the day will come when you're going to want to hook your
corporate networks up with your VPCs and we saw that actually earlier in the course using VPNs and Direct Connect.
So, a bit of a long winded answer, but I reckon the biggest mistake and probably one of the easiest to make
is getting your VPC networking wrong. So yeah, networking, get it right from the start because unpicking
a fundamental problem like duplicate CIDR blocks, it's about as much fun as, I don't know waxing your armpit hair,
not that I've ever done that, obviously. Really I haven't. But you get the message, right?
Unpicking network problems is not fun.