Right, so I'm Nigel and for those of you who don't know me yet, I love technology, properly love it.
I think ever since I first programmed my brother's ZX Spectrum 48K, the rubber key version for anyone
who remembers it, right. Well I think since then I've wanted to spend my life with computers, I just love them.
I'm fascinated by them. The idea that I can make them do things and then when things go wrong I can dig
under the covers and fix them, it's a bit like a drug for me. And Amazon Web Services is no different.
Well, obviously it's massively different to an old Spectrum 48K, right, but the principles and stuff
are all the same. It is exciting and it's a game changer. Anyway, I love working and playing with technology
and I love teaching you guys about it. Now aside from technology, I'm really into fitness.
I play a lot of football, I like lifting weights, riding my bike, running, all that kind of stuff, okay,
and I support the mighty Sunderland, the greatest Football team in the world.
Also, I'm a husband to the lovely Jen and I'm father to three girls that are going to change the world,
if they want to. I know they certainly changed mine. Anyway, I love making these courses for you.
They're a ton of fun and one of my main objectives, right, is for you guys to have fun watching them.
I really do want your learning experience to be enjoyable. Okay, and a massive thanks, right, to everyone
who reaches out and tells me how much they enjoy my courses, and also all those guys who ping me and tell me
how excited they are when I've created a new one. Thank you so much.
I love you guys. But on that note actually, right, I really want to make every course that I do better
than the last one. And to do that, I totally need your help. So yeah, I love all the love that you give my courses,
honestly I really do, but if there's anything that you reckon I could do better next time, seriously,
I want you to tell me. So hit the course discussion board
on Pluralsight.com or ping me on twitter. I really value your feedback and input into my next courses
and how's about this, right, together we can make the next course better.
A bit cheese, right? I know, but it's true. You want the next course that I do for you to be better than this one?
Ping me and help me, right.
Ah, yeah, I nearly forgot. Also, right, I co-host a weekly podcast called the In Tech We Trust Podcast
and it's dedicated to infrastructure tech news, so all about keeping you up-to-date with what's going on
in the infrastructure tech world and we talk about Amazon Web Services and the likes all the time.
So if you're into this stuff, I recommend you give it a listen. Now then,
this is how we're going to do this course. In the next module I'm going to do like a super quick high level overview
of AWS and virtual private clouds, which I'm probably just going to call VPCs from now on.
Then after that, we're going to build a VPC, but using the wizard, and that works and all, but it's just not
very good for learning how it all works under the covers. So after that, we're going to hand build a VPC.
We'll hand build subnets and configure routing, we'll configure access to the internet, we'll lock things down
with network access control lists and security groups, then we'll start adding some of the cool stuff.
First up, we'll do elastic load balancers, then we'll configure VPC peering where we hook up some string
between two VPCs, then after that we'll look at how we hook up remote offices to our VPC using a
virtual private network or a VPN connection, and when we're done with all that good stuff we'll round out the module
with a short sharp Q&A session and I've never done one of these before, right, but what I'm going to do is
I'm going to answer what I see as some of the most common AWS questions.
And the answers, of course, they'll all just be my opinions, but I don't know, I'm hoping that it might be
a cool little module. Then that'll be done. Anyway, that's enough of that, right.
Time to go and actually start learning about AWS virtual private clouds.
And as we can see here, I'm going to start the ball rolling in the next module by introducing the high level concept
and running through the major technologies that we're going to be configuring.