So we're going to kick this baby off by making our public subnet, well public.
Now according to the Amazon docs and the likes, in order for a subnet to be public, it needs to be connected to
an internet gateway. Okay, fair play. In practice though, there's a bit more to it than that, like it needs
to have a route to the internet and then there's the small matter of having a public IP address, but we'll get
into those in just a second. For now, let's just create an internet gateway and while we go along
we'll explain what it is. So if we hit Internet Gateways over here, and we're going to create a new one,
well check that out. All it needs is a name. Talk about a simple setup.
I mean step back for just a second and really think about that. Life back in the day, right, when I was
cutting my infrastructure teeth. You know what, and cutting my fingers racking and stacking servers
in small coms rooms, back in the 90's. Well, I remember when we got our first ever 1 MB internet connection.
I mean, this was like a huge deal, not just the fact that it cost an arm and a leg and 1 MB was like
mahoosive, but the effort that we went to to make it as redundant as possible and the likes, wow, I mean
I remember we had a couple of our own routers hooked up to it, and although I was definitely a trusted member
of IT, I was nowhere near senior enough to go anywhere near it. I mean it was a huge deal.
We practically had the queen come and ceremoniously commission the thing.
It was a big deal and it was a ton of effort and money. Well you know what?
With a click of a button, and well let's give it a name here as well (Typing) and as simple as that,
we've created for ourselves, where is it? I wrote this down somewhere, here we go.
We've just created for ourselves a horizontally scaled, redundant, highly available internet connection.
Talk about buzz word bingo. Let me run that by you again, a horizontally scaled, redundant, highly available
internet connection, so posing no availability risks and no bandwidth or scalability constraints.
I mean is somebody pulling my chain here or what? I've just clicked maybe like three buttons and supposedly
I've got what sounds like the ultimate in high speed, never goes down, internet connections.
Seriously, sounds the bizzo, right? But here's I suppose the frustrating part, yeah.
Amazon doesn't tell us anything about how it actually is all that stuff, so no detail to backup any of those
impressive claims. You know, so how do you make it horizontally scalable or highly available or how does it
achieve no bandwidth constraints Mr. Amazon? I mean I'm an inquisitive guy, right, I want to know.
Their response, you don't really want to know. Uh, yeah actually I do want to know.
No, you don't. Sure I do want to know. You don't want to know.
I want to know. I want the truth. You can't handle the truth. Anyway, the point is, we've got these
awesome claims from Amazon, but nothing to back them up with. Again, we've just got to take their word for it,
yeah, but every bummer. I suppose the point being, right, creating a potentially awesome internet connection
for your VPC and its subnets is like a Sunday afternoon stroll in the park.
All we need to do now is attach it to our VPC. Oh and notice the drop down, it's only giving us VPCs
that don't already have one. So it's a one internet gateway to one VPC mapping.
I suppose what else would it be, right? I mean, why you would want two of them when they're indestructible
and never tire, makes sense right? Okay, anyway, that's our uber high performance, uber available
internet gateway created. Even my mom could have done it. But notice, okay, that it got associated
with our VPC, not a specific subnet. So it's available to all of our subnets, we just need to create entries
in a subnet's route table to enable that subnet to use it. So why don't we.