First things first okay, create the VPC. Now we're going to see that a VPC itself is not much more than a name
and a range of IP addresses or at least that's all that we need to worry about.
Remember, right, behind the scenes we are carving out for ourselves a portion of Amazon's world class
data center infrastructure. Anyway okay, we're going to call ours podcast again.
I deleted the one that we used in the last module and I did a bit of cleaning up.
Then we'll go with a 10.0 network again. Remember, this /16 means that the first 2 octets are the network address
and the last 2 octets here are for device addresses. We'll get this bit right, okay, because you know what?
Like most network hocus pocus, once it's done it is like way to complicated to change.
So get your CIDR block right because there's no way to come back and change it later.
Now, I suppose what do I mean when I say get it right? Well, you're going to want to do things like
make sure that you're not already using this CIDR block somewhere else in your corporate network, even outside
of AWS, okay. Because if you are and then at some time in the future you come and try and hook that network up
to AWS file, like a VPN or something, well you're going to have problems.
So, the moral of the story here, make sure that this CIDR block is unique within your organization, yeah.
Then tenancy here, yeah, this is just whether or not we want to pay for our own dedicated physical servers
on the back end or whether we're happy to share. I'm happy to share.
Okay. Now, remember, a VPC only exists within a region. So here's our VPC and up here, I'm in Ireland,
true that be. Apologies to any fine Irish people watching, that was my shocking attempt at an Irish accent,
but if I go to let's say Asia Pac Sydney, good day mate, well we can see here how there's just the default VPC
in this region. So when building a VPC, make sure that you're in the right region, oh, and if at some time
in the future you're looking around for your VPC and you can't fine it and you're like, ahh where's my VPC gone?
Amazon's lost my VPC, my entire world. Well, don't sweat. Well I'm saying don't sweat, at least double check first
that you're in the right region. I've been there and done that in the past, you know, got the cold sweats
thinking, where's my VPC gone, it's disappeared. Only then to realize, nah, I was just in the wrong region.
Okay, point taken I'm sure. Let me get back to the Emerald Isle.
Okay let's take a look now at some of the VPC related config.