So here's the deal, right, so far we've configured this like uber network, our data center for ourselves, right,
inside of Amazon Web Services and a module or two back we put a couple of public facing web servers in there
and then we stuck a load balancer in front of them, all good stuff.
Oh, and we've seen a few times as well how we can connect to our instances using SSH or if they're Windows,
yeah that would be RDP, but the thing to note, right, all of this kind of access has come into our VPC
through its internet gateway, so all using publically routable IPs and unless we use secure protocols
like SSH or HTTPS, then it's all totally unencrypted. So, we're talking over the internet, right,
and then wide open for anyone to look at. Now, okay, all we've done so far, right, is a bit of HTTP action
to a static webpage or two with like 0 sensitive content, but there's like absolutely nothing stopping us
from hosting, I don't know, mail servers or database servers or whatever in our VPC.
In fact, we probably want to do stuff like that, but of course, as soon as we do, then the kind of traffic
we're going to be sending is almost certainly going to be more sensitive.
Well, if that's the case then we want to connect to those services from outside of AWS, so probably
from our corporate office, yeah, well we've got a couple of options.
We can either secure each and every connection type, so maybe configure our client so that they only talk
to the mail servers over secure protocols or the same for our database servers, yeah, only allow clients
to talk to them via secure protocols, or we can configure a secure virtual private network, a VPN,
or a tunnel. So that would go from our corporate office all the way to our VPC.
That way, right, everything that we send between our office and the VPC goes through this tunnel
and is therefore automatically encrypted and nice and secure. And you know what?
Of the two options, I don't know like 99. whatever % of the time, option 2 is going to be the one
and that's the deal with AWS VPNs. We take our office, so branch office, home office, corporate HQ,
whatever, right, and we lash it up to our VPC over a VPN connection.
And boom, right, in one fell swoop we've made all communications between the two secure.
How come? Well like we just said, this connection between the two sites here, it's secure, IPsec secure,
if that means anything to you. Basically, all traffic, so in both directions, is encrypted using IPsec.
And I think we've hinted at this, but let's just be clear right now, we sometimes call this connection here
the tunnel. I don't know, how's about this for an analogy, so we're connecting via the internet, yeah,
and we know everyone's on the internet including the bad guys. Well, to keep the bad guys from spying
on our chatter, we create this tunnel and then you can only get in and out of the tunnel from either end.
But each end is already secure, right, or it should be, so in our VPC we'll be using things like NACLs
and security groups and the likes, and then over in our remote office we'll be using similar stuff,
or we should be. The point being, the bad guys out here are outside of our tunnel and from outside,
you can't see or get in, so a bit like, and I did say we were going to get an analogy here, so I don't know,
a bit like you know how famous people travel around in big old cars with blacked out windows so you can't
see in from the outside? Well it's a bit like that. We're all using the same roads and the likes,
but you can see straight into the likes of my car, right? So you can see who's inside, what the kids are
watching on their iPads or DVD players, probably see my wife having a sleep in the passenger seat,
but cars with blacked out windows, good luck seeing what's going on inside of them.
Well a VPN tunnel it's a bit like that. We're all traveling about on the internet, yeah, but VPN tunnels
are encrypted so if you're on the outside you can't see in. Okay, now in a way, right, the office location here,
well it becomes almost like just another subnet within our VPC and that is massive, right?
It literally means that resources in each network, so from either end of the tunnel, can access resources
in the other network as if they were set right by each other, the key being using private IPs, yes.
No more having to assign public IPs to resources that you only want to use internally.
And also, this VPN, right, it's a permanent, always up, highly available, encrypted tunnel between the office here
and our AWS VPC. Now that is a far cry, okay, from the flaky old VPN connections that I relied on
as an IT support engineer all those years ago back in the early days of my career.
The kind of VPNs we're working with here with AWS, they are rock solid, they're nothing like the VPNs
of the bad old days. Anyway, that's the high level, okay. Now, let's go and drill down a bit to the actual
bits and pieces that we need to get it all working.