So I'm all logged into AWS here. We're going to want to jump into the VPC section, which is down here
under Network, and then this old boy up here is what we want, Start VPC Wizard.
Now then, at the time of recording, and it's been like this for awhile actually, but we've got four options,
only it's pretty much two options with just a slight variation on each.
What am I talking about? Well, we've got VPC with a Single Subnet up here, then underneath we've got VPC
with Public and Private Subnets. And then the two options below down here, these are just the same,
but with a VPN bolted on. No matter though, don't get bogged down right now, we'll cover all things
in all their glorious detail as we get further into the course. Right now though we're going to rock and roll
with option 2. We'll have a public and a private subnet, thank you very much.
Oh, and a nice pretty picture here, and yeah, why not, seeing as how I'm a fan of learning by repetition
and the likes, let's give this a quick mention while we're here.
This outer square here, okay, what's that? Well, okay, it's a rectangle not a square, but you're with me,
this outer rectangle, this is our entire VPC, our entire virtual data center that we're building,
then within it we're creating two subnets, a public one, and a private one.
Now the major difference or the only difference, to be honest, is that a public subnet is going to have
direct access to the internet. We're going to be able to connect out to the wider world as well as accept
unsolicited incoming connections. The private subnet on the other hand isn't.
Well, yeah, actually that'll do for now.
Oh, scary screen. Well, not really. Up here at the top, okay, this is the VPC stuff, subnet specific stuff
is below, and we'll get to that in a second. First up, the easy stuff though, VPC name.
I'm going to call this one podcast. Now then, the CIDR block, okay, this is where we define the network
or the network addresses from which all of our subnets will take their addresses from.
I don't know, right, think of it as like a master network, like a pool of addresses that all of our subnets
will then be a slice of and I know, okay, for the network savvy who are watching, I'm sure I butchered that,
but suffice to say, okay, whatever we choose here at the VPC definition level, our subnets have to draw from.
So we can't do something like 10.0.0.0 up here and then try and pick subnet address ranges down here
from let's just say 192.168.whatever, yeah. Look scary red text, never a good sign.
An actually, okay, while I'm not an uber networking guy, I am from a strong infrastructure background.
And you know what? I've held some Cisco certs in the dim and distant past.
So for those that might not know, okay, let's wipe this onto the screen here, yeah, okay, so IPv4 addresses
like these are broken down into 4 octets, 4 sets of 8 bits, 8, 16, 24, and 32.
And then by slapping /16 onto the end here, we're basically saying the first 16 bits or the first 2 octets,
so the numbers before the first 2 periods, these are network address.
I don't know, maybe like the city name in our postal address. In this case then we'd be in the 10.0 city,
then the remaining 2 octets are for street and house numbers of any devices that we put onto the network.
So the number after the /16 here is telling us how many bits constitute the network portion of the address,
then we're free to play with any bits that are left over to the right of that, in this case the last 2 octets, yeah.
Probably a totally garbage analogy I know, but who knows, right, maybe it helps somebody.
I'm trying hard to remember here that not all of you are going to be from an infrastructure background like me.
Anyway, let's clean this mess up.