First up, right, let's just see the concept, you know, in case load balancing is like totally new to you
or maybe it's just a bit of a gray area for you. One of those, you know, where you're maybe not so confident about it,
but you don't really want to ask anyone in case you look a bit daft.
Hey, we've all been there at one time or another, right. So a dead simple diagram.
Two availability zones, eu-west 1b and eu-west 1a. Okay, I obviously got those the wrong way around
when cutting and pasting, never mind. Two availability zones, so two data centers, yeah, with a bunch of
instances in each. Now let's say for arguments sake, okay, these are internet facing web servers
and they're all serving up the same web front end for an app, well what we love to do, right, is balance
incoming traffic from the internet across all of these instances and have it rigged up in a way so that if an instance
goes down or even a whole availability zone, so a major incident, yeah, we don't skip a beat.
We've have it so that the surviving infrastructure just carries on.
Sounds the bizzo, yeah. Well, meet the elastic load balancer and a fancy new icon for us as well, right.
Well, this guy or gal, this becomes our internet facing component, so almost like a single point of contact
for our farm of web front end servers that we've got. Then as such it knows about all of our web server instances
behind it, so that as requests come in it balances those requests over all the instances it knows about.
You know what? A bit like at airport security, yeah, where there's a bunch of lines queuing to go through
the checkpoint and often there's someone there directing you to the shortest line, only they usually send you
to the longest line, right, or at least they do with me. Well, elastic load balancing works a bit like that.
Directing and balancing incoming traffic over multiple instances behind it.
And if we look closely enough, we can see that it's load balancing across availability zones, so our instances
don't need to be all in the same availability zone, though I should point out they do need to be in the same VPC,
at least at the time of recording they do. And obviously, knock-on effect to that means it only works
for AWS services, so we can get carried away and start load balancing across multiple cloud providers
like Microsoft Azure and Google Cloud platform. And that extends even to on-prem for that matter, right.
So ELB right now is only for load balancing across infrastructure within a single VPC in the AWS cloud.
And it can do health checks too. So it keeps an eye on the instances that it knows about behind it
so that if and when any of them stop responding, they get taken out of the load balancing config,
though actually no, they don't really get taken out of the config, they just get marked as down
and the ELB no longer sends requests to them. But because they're still in the config, once they're back up
and running, they can automatically be brought back into play. What else?
Ah, yeah, it integrates with auto scaling as well. So as in when auto scaling, as long as we've got it
configured, yeah, decides that we need more web servers spinning up, they can all be added into the ELB config
and start having traffic balanced over them as well. Sounds the absolute bizzo to me.
So what are we actually going to build?
Well, we're going to introduce an elastic load balancer into our VPC and we're going to configure it
to listen for incoming web traffic and balance those requests across instances in two public facing subnets,
and that's magic, but we're only scratching the surface here. We can add a ton more to the mix.
Maybe we could start load balancing internal traffic from our front end web servers to a distributed database
back end in a couple of highly available private subnets. This way we could lose an entire availability zone
or anything in it and keep on rocking. All this stuff down here that's not been effected, it just keeps ticking.
Because remember, availability zones don't effect or impact each other, or at least they shouldn't.
So losing one is not such a massive deal, I mean it is a big deal, right, because your remaining infrastructure
is probably going to struggle to manage the entire load on its own, but it's certainly not going to take
your entire application or your entire business down with it, and that is a monster sized boon, right.
So I reckon the things to grasp and learn, right, are elastic load balancers are resilient and they're not tied
to an availability zone. So losing one, an availability zone, yeah, isn't going to take the elastic load balancer
service out of play, and assuming we've got our app set up properly, we stay in business.
And that there to me is a pretty sweet highly available design. Should we go and build it?