So let's draw out a picture, yeah, but for clarity and so we don't get distracted, I'm just going to keep it
simple, okay. I'll leave out some of the AWS detail that we already know, like availability zones and stuff.
Alright, let's say then we've got a couple of subnets, 1 and 2, with a couple of instances in each.
And the up top here, we've got our VPC's router. Now the normal flow of traffic is that traffic comes into
the router, so could be from the internet or from another subnet or from another VPC even, the point being
traffic comes into our router, then depending on the routes in the route table, the router sends the traffic on.
So, if it's intended for one of our subnets it gets sent on there.
And that's it really. So where security groups and network ACLs come into play, it's like this, as traffic
gets routed to a subnet the network A-C-L or ACL or whatever you want to call it, associated with that subnet
inspects the traffic and then based on the rules in the ACL, it decides whether or not to allow the traffic.
So maybe the ACL says web traffic from the internet is allowed, but SSH traffic isn't unless it comes from
a machine with an IP address from our management network. Well then, anytime any SSH traffic comes in
from anywhere other than the management network it's going to get dropped, not allowed through.
And as we can see, or at least as I'm trying to show here with the padlock, and you will see that on official
AWS diagrams, the network ACL lives and works at the subnet level, so it gets applied to subnets
and therefore protects any instances in those subnets. Security groups, on the other hand, which are sometimes
seen in AWS diagrams like this, well these get associated with individual instances, a bit like
instance firewalls, well a lot like them actually. So, you know, like the Windows firewall or IP tables
or maybe some third party software, yeah. The point being, they're local to the instance.
But actually, right, a bit like public and elastic IPs, our instances don't actually know anything about them,
so they get applied or kind of wrapped around the instance. So we manage and we configure them at the AWS level
from the AWS console. If we were to log onto our instances and look at local firewalls and the likes,
they know nothing about them. Anyway, as we can see, right, two layers of security.
So any traffic that gets past the network ACL has got another hurdle to jump before it makes it to the instance,
and that's good stuff, defense in-depth, layered security, all of that goodness.
And that's the thing to digest I reckon, right. We've got two layers, two complimentary layers.
I think I'm going to say this a lot, right, defense in-depth. Well that's the view from like 50,000 light years.
Let's zoom in a bit closer next and look at security groups.