So first up, right, I called the module configuring routing between VPCs.
But the way we do this is via an AWS technology called VPC peering.
So there are totally times, right, where we want to hook up a couple of VPCs, in a way though
so that resources in either VPC can talk to the other VPC without having to cross the internet
and I hate lists of bullet points, right, but I don't know, I can't really escape it here.
Anyway, this, right, is where VPC peering comes into play. So, any two VPCs lashed together with a
peering connection actually, that's our first point. These peering connections are 1 to 1.
Sure, a VPC can be paired up with a whole bunch of other VPCs, but that requires a whole bunch of
individual connections. Reason being, every connection requires its own connection object, it'll be
crystal clear in a second. Anyway, this is all about private IPs, yeah, and this is the bizzo,
I mean it means we don't have to worry about changeable public IPs or chargeable elastic IPs,
and in general, it's just a bit more secure, yeah. Oh, peering is region specific, so the VPC's we want to
lash together need to be in the same region. We can't do this stuff across region yet.
Hmm, okay, maybe I should have mentioned this when saying peering connections are 1 to 1, so as the slide says,
right, peering connections are not transitive. This means if we've got three VPCs, 1, 2, and 3 here,
and 1's connected to 2 and 2's connected to 3, this does not mean that 1 is connected to 3.
It's not. There's none of this, don't mind me, I'm just passing through.
No you're not. This old boy here, VPC 2 is not a transit point between 1 and 3.
If 1 wants to talk to 3 as a peer, it needs its own connection. Oh yeah, kind of similar.
We can only have one peering connection between any two VPCs. So no doubling up for performance or resiliency,
yeah or no. But don't sweat about that, at least if you believe Amazon, because according to them,
although they won't tell you how, VPC peering connections have no single point of failure and they're so bad ass,
right, they're never going to be a choking point in your network.
Okay, well that's what they say. Ah, right, so this is like uber important okay.
None of this is going to work if the network address space in one VPC, so the CIDR block that we configure it with,
overlaps with the other VPC. They need to be on totally separate CIDR blocks and this runs through our
VPC networking, right. If you want to connect any network up to a VPC, so maybe lash up a link between your
corporate office and your VPC over a VPN or direct connect that we're going to talk about in the next module,
or even what we're going here, connecting VPCs, we can never have overlapping CIDR blocks.
Okay, so what happens is from within one VPC we create a connection request requesting a peer connection
to another VPC. And that VPC, okay, can totally belong to another AWS account, in fact, we're going to do that
later with two separate accounts, but we create this connection request from the source VPC, though
there's no real concept of source and destination. Anyway, that request, it then pops up in the VPC console
of the destination VPC. Then the owner or the admin of that VPC has got like a week or something to accept it
or reject it. And I totally advise you to be extremely carefully accepting peering requests.
You don't want some evil dude spoofing a connection to you and you accepting it because bad things
would almost certainly ensue. Anyway, once that's accepted each VPC gains a peering connection object,
kind of like an internet gateway, yeah, and it's like totally uber remember, unbreakable and impossible
to overrun. Then one last thing, we've got to update the routing tables associated with the subnets
that we want using this connection. No doubt, right, some bits are probably still a bit vague,
but I reckon, right, once we've run through our mock scenario and we've actually gone and configured it all,
I reckon it will feel like you've known it forever, inside out and back to front.
So let's go and look at our scenario.