So at the very highest level AWS is a public cloud platform, which I suppose begs the question, what is
a public cloud platform? And you know what? I don't want to get into a religious war here, so don't expect this
to be some like Q-rated Wikipedia style uber definition, I'm just trying to get the ball rolling for the
course here. Anyway, so back in the day, right, Amazon was running probably the biggest online retail website
in the world and the website itself was the crops of their business, right?
So they invested in it. It was high performance, highly available, all of that stuff, and it had
spare capacity. So one day, and I'm cutting this story horrifically short here and I'm leaving out names
that absolutely deserve mentioning, but one day, let's just call them the folks at Amazon, had the idea,
well the admittedly brilliant and game changing idea, hey why don't we sell some of this spare capacity
to customers. Oh my goodness. I mean, it is so simple in hindsight, but what a revolutionary idea that was.
The idea, yeah, that there's this mahoosive web scale infrastructure out there that's highly available,
high performing, and whatever else, and you can buy or actually, I should say, rent, slices of it.
I mean, who wouldn't want some of that? So let's say you're a startup or in fact you're any business that
needs to grow, but you don't want to lay down a bunch of capital to build your own data center and buy your
own servers and storage, instead you can just go and rent some of it from Amazon.
They'll be more than happy to sell you a bunch of compute and storage, the full shebang, and guess what?
They probably build and manage it better than you do. Okay, well let's say business is good and you're expecting
a spike in business next month and you think maybe you need to double or triple or quadruple your needs,
but then you're projecting that maybe a month or so after that you don't need it anymore.
No sweat. That's what this stuff is all about. It's elastic. You can just spin up more virtual machines
or consume more storage space or whatever and pay for what you use and then if you stop using it,
you stop paying. And don't forget, it's all built on top of world class infrastructure.
I'll have some of that, thanks. Now while we're on,
AWS as a cloud platform, okay, is architected into regions and availability zones.
So, at a global level AWS has got data centers in strategic locations around the world.
This map is not bang up-to-date because it doesn't have the EU central region in Frankfurt, but it gives you
the idea, right. In certain strategic locations Amazon builds data centers.
These locations then get called regions. And now to every region Amazon offers certain AWS services.
I live in the UK, so my closest AWS region is Ireland EU West. If I lived in Chicago, then it would be
Northern Virginia, US East. The idea being, right, well there's actually a few architectural design decisions
behind it all, but probably the simplest yeah is that regions closer to where you are going to be faster,
but also, and I suppose, well maybe more important, every region is fully independent, so fully isolated
from all other regions. Meaning, if a service in a region or in fact if the entire region itself goes down,
other regions shouldn't be impacted. Then if we drill down a bit,
within each region, and this is the standard way of drawing an AWS region, within each region we've got
two or more availability zones. If we use Ireland, EU-West as an example, it's got three availability zones.
Each connected, yeah, by a high speed, low latency network links.
Now then, each availability zone is physically isolated from the rest, meaning if one of them goes down,
I don't know a power issue or rock falls from space onto it, whatever, other availability zones in that region
won't be affected. But, and even AWS has buts, there have been plenty of services outages, okay, where issues
have started in one availability zone and rippled over into other availability zones, causing the effected service
to choke and become unavailable across the entire region. So that's why I was careful to say, right,
availability zones are highly available and isolated from a physical perspective.
From a logical service and API perspective, they're often still coupled in some way, certainly at least
more coupled than regions. So I guess then, for like uber high availability, you might want to be spreading
your services across regions, though actually I'm saying that, that's a bit of a two-edged sword
because we don't have these nice low latency links between regions.
Anyway, feels like we're starting to get into the weeds, too early for that, so back to the picture.
It's like this in all regions, okay. They've all got at least two availability zones, actually I'm saying that,
all the ones that I have used have. I think that's pretty standard architecture actually.
Now then, okay, so as we spin up resources, so like virtual machines, which AWS calls instances,
we pick which region and which availability zone we want to spin them up in.
This way we can make our apps and our infrastructure highly available by spreading them over availability zones
and regions. And I reckon that's a half decent quick look at AWS.
So what about VPCs?