Now bear with me here actually okay, you see I listen to a lot of audio books, audible.com, yeah,
and I'm mighty impressed actually by some of the narrators. They're like really cool at voices and accents,
so I figure, it can't be that hard can it? So I'm going to give it a try.
So here it goes. Next question, uh yeah, hi Nigel, Anna here from UberInfrastructure.com.
What would say is the most misunderstood AWS VPC concept? Thanks Anna.
I'd probably say some of the auto scaling stuff, but that's not directly VPC related or at least auto scaling
is not configured from the VPC console, so it's not included in the course.
I guess then I'd better choose something that we did cover in the course.
Maybe private and public IPs. So you know when we launch instances into our VPCs?
Those instances automatically get private IPs, but obviously we can't talk directly to instances
using those private IPs unless we're connecting over a VPN or Direct Connect, which by the way,
is why VPNs and Direct Connect are so cool. But when we do assign public IPs to instances, the instance itself,
so Linux or whatever iOS you're using, well it's got zero knowledge of that public IP.
It knows absolutely nothing about it. So I mean if you log on and run host based IP commands like ifconfig
and IP and the likes, you're only going to see private IPs. Public IPs are totally abstracted from instances.
No, not abstracted, decoupled. The internet gateway in your VPC is what makes the magic of public IPs work.
So, the internet gateway, right, it keeps a table that maps public IP addresses to instances or to
network interfaces on instances. Basically, right routing any traffic that comes inbound for those
public IP addresses to the private IPs of the instances. So I guess for all practical intents and purposes,
our instances do have public IPs, it's just that behind the scenes AWS does a bunch of smoke and mirror stuff
on the internet gateway to make it all happen. And while we're on public IPs actually, it's really common
for folks to forget or you know what, maybe not even know, that normal public IPs in AWS, they change
every time you reboot an instance. So, they're cool, but they're totally unreliable.
For reliable public IPs, ones that are going to stick with our instance, even after reboots,
we need elastic IPs, and last I checked, every AWS account is limited to five elastic IPs per region.
And they cost money, another reason, right, for using VPNs and Direct Connect.
Anyway, I'm blabbering again, but I think the main points to note are that normal public IPs in AWS
change when you reboot an instance and elastic IPs don't. But you pay for elastic IPs and you're initially
limited to five per region per account, though you can request more.
Hope that answered your question.