Well, first up, right, the obvious stuff. We need a working VPC and we need a remote office location.
And I know that's totally obvious okay, but like we said in the previous module about VPC peering,
these two locations, our office and our VPC, they absolutely must have totally separate networks.
So that means zero overlapping of address spaces or CIDR blocks.
For example, right, we can't have the 10.0 network over here and then use it again over here in our VPC,
well I mean, we totally can and they'll work in isolation, but try and lash them together with a VPN,
that's a whole different story. So like we said way, way back at the beginning of the course, right from day 0
you've got to treat your VPC just like a regular old corporate network, so that means give it its own
documented IP range and make sure that you don't use that IP range anywhere else in the company.
Sure our VPC is out in AWS and it kind of might not feel like it's part of the corporate network, but by
lashing it up with a VPN or something, it totally can be. So treat it like any old site and any other network
that you would on your corporate infrastructure. But to build this, right, we pretty need to configure
three things. First we need to configure what AWS calls a customer gateway and for now, right, we can
think of this as our end of the VPN, the bit of kit in our office that terminates the VPN tunnel
and it's usually going to be a dedicated piece of hardware, like a firewall or a VPN router or something.
Next, we need to configure a virtual private gateway. This is the other end of the tunnel, the end that terminates
the connection inside of AWS. Then once we've got both ends, we need to configure the VPN itself,
the tunnel, yeah. And this is basically just logically connecting the two, bringing the two together
to form the tunnel. And go on, it's analogy time again, okay, so maybe think of the two ends of the tunnel,
the customer gateway and the virtual private gateway, as being like, I don't know, rail terminals, yeah,
at each end of a tunnel. Something like the channel tunnel that connects London to Paris, yeah.
Well, the only way in and out of that tunnel is via those terminals, then this last bit that we configure here,
the tunnel, is like all the config details needed to get the two ends of the tunnel talking to each other
and ready to let trains through. I don't know, signaling and speed limits and stuff like that, yeah.
Well the same goes for our VPN config, these two items here are like the rail terminals if you will,
and then the VPN config itself is defining how the tunnel will work.
I don't know it was probably a crappy analogy, okay, but we're talking about things like which customer gateway
will be on our end and which virtual private gateway will be on the AWS end.
Then we'll configure routing options, encryption, and stuff like that.
And you know what? If we look over here
at our VPC console, right, those three steps that we just mentioned, they correspond nicely to these three
options down here and literally in that order, one, two, three. The customer gateway, our end of the tunnel,
the virtual private gateway, Amazon's end of the tunnel, and then the VPN config that brings the tunnel up
and makes it operational. So that's the three steps okay. But before we dive in and do it, just a few
quick points.
First up, right, it's important to grok that this virtual private gateway here is a device of sorts, okay,
and it kind of exists in our VPC. So, it can be addressed in our route tables, right, just like an internet gateway,
but realize, right, that it's a totally different object to an internet gateway.
So once we've got it up and working in our VPC, all traffic between our VPC and our remote office,
which here is defined as the 10.1 network is going to go across the virtual private gateway and not
the internet gateway. And like we hinted at before, this traversing of the VPN connection is what lets us
use private IPs when communicating between the two networks rather than having to use internet routable
public IPs, and that's good stuff. Also, right, the virtual private gateway, it's the cha-zing.
So if we explode it out a bit, yeah, it really looks more like this.
So two distinct end points IP addresses, yeah, in a highly available or a redundant design.
Now I don't know the implementation specifics behind this, right, but I would expect it to be more than just
a couple of ports on the same piece of hardware. I'd expect it to be more like two ports spread over
two different devices, I don't know, probably in two different cabinets and maybe in two different holes
or two different facilities. The whole idea being, right, it's highly available.
So if one of those endpoints goes down, the other stands a pretty good chance of staying up.
But this is one of those instances, right, where we've got to trust AWS as a platform.
They're not going to give us the secret source behind how it all works and how it's all highly available,
we've just got to trust that it's there and that it will be available and that's the big take away point, right.
We totally want to think of this as a VPN concentrator service, yes, it's highly available, yes
it's high performance, yeah, it's the bizzo. But we don't need to get bogged down by all of the detail.
We just use it and it's there when we need it. But what we're looking at here is only half of the picture, yeah,
we absolutely can and you know what, if we care at all about the availability of this tunnel then we
absolutely should build a similar HA design at our end. So yeah, we totally can rig it up so that we've got
two customer gateways on our end, hooked up, cross connected, multi-pathed, call it whatever you want, right,
to each of those virtual private gateway endpoints on the AWS end.
This way, right, when, and I say when on purpose, right, when any one individual component goes down,
the surviving links here, they just kick in and take over. The VPN service, no sweat, right, remains up
and working. Move along guys, nothing to see here, business as usual, yeah.
Ah, and one more point, okay, you definitely want your own static IPs over here.
And I know that's often par for the course, right, with office internet connections, but it's not always the case
for home offices. So if you're trying to hook your home office up to your AWS VPC, you want a broadband package
or an internet package or whatever, that guarantees you a static IP.
Otherwise, right, anytime your IP changes, like maybe when you reboot your router or whatever, then
you're going to need to reconfigure your whole tunnel again and that can be a royal pain in the rear.
And on that note, right, I think we'll get off the slides and over to our AWS console.