But check out the diagram, right. If you've been following along from the start you're probably thinking,
hang on, there's like a ton of stuff on there that we haven't even got yet.
I mean it's not stuff that we haven't covered, it's just stuff that we have covered, but we haven't built yet.
I'm not explaining this well. Just as an example, right, so we've only got one public subnet and one private subnet
and we've not built any web servers yet either. So that's what we're going to do right now, build all of this
missing stuff. But I'm going to leverage the marvels of video editing so we can literally wiz through it
like superman style. So first up,
I'm going to create a couple of security groups and seeing as how I've clean a few things up, I don't need
any of these anymore (Typing). Okay, don't care about the default one, that's fine.
Now two new security groups, one for HTTP traffic, and another for SSH.
Now we need a couple of subnets, but let's rename these first to tack on the availability zone, because that's
going to become really important from now on. Now we want to know the public one, make sure it's got an
internet gateway associated with the public NACL that we created before, and I reckon that one's ready.
Now under the private one, you keeping up? We'll make sure it's not connected to the internet, no,
give it the wide open NACL for now, oh man, flying through it like this is good.
We've already got our four subnets, two public, both in separate availability zones, and two private,
also both in separate availability zones. So, if, let's say, I don't know, a fracture in the space time continuum
opened up and swallowed up eu-west 1b, well, who cares about that, right, we've got our service, or we will
have our services I should say, running in 1b and 1a, so we'd hardly even notice.
Anyway, we need a couple of web servers now and this time I'm going to create those with the wave of my hand,
and there they are. So two web servers, right, one in each of our public subnets, and they're essentially
the same. Both of them have just got a single webpage that's almost identical except for the fact that
each has got some individual text on there so we can tell which one it is, because we're going to need that
when we start using the load balancer in a second. But before we use the load balancer, right, if I grab
1a's IP address and lash that into a browser session, there we go, Server 1a.
And the same again for 1b, magic, same again, but with its own unique identifier.
Cool. All of that done. Let's go and build ourselves an elastic load balancer.