So I'm going to go with 10.1 as the network for my VPC here.
Then down in our subnet we're going to have 10.1.0 and 10.1.1. Okay, still loads of red text.
So, if we stick /24 onto the end of it, what we're basically saying okay is that the network portion of the addresses
for our subnets is actually the first 24 bits, so 10.1.0 and 10.1.1 and then because they're both slices
of the bigger 10.1 network that we've got up here in our VPC, the scary red text goes away and everything
looks good again. Now then, I don't know how many of you have picked up on this, but despite this bit here
being a config for our public subnet, the fact is any network address starting with 10.anything is de facto
and de jure, not a public network. 10.anything addresses are like full on RFC 1918 addresses, which is technical
uber jargon meaning they're just not publicly routable on the internet.
In proper layman's terms here, right, any internet router that sees packets with addresses like this
is just going to drop those packets. Here we go. Maybe time for a quick, I don't know, probably crappy
analogy again, right, but trying to talk to a device with a 10. address over the public internet, that's a bit like
trying to send internal office mail via the national postal service.
So just think, I don't know, an internal mail address to Mike in accounts on the 7th floor or Mia in facilities
on the 5th floor, right. The national post man or post woman, they're going to take one look at that address
and probably the lack of a stamp, yeah, and just say, what? I can't deliver that.
And they're just going to bin it. But I'm waffling, right? If our 10. public network here isn't publicly
routable, so not routable on the internet, then how the chuff is it going to work as a public subnet?
I mean public subnets are all about communicating directly with the internet, right?
And yeah you are right, they are. But you know what? I'm going to unfold this mystery in just a second.
For now, let's just put it down to AWS magic, okay. I mean it's not and we'll see exactly how it's done
in all of its simplistic glory in just a second, but let's not get side tracked yet.
I just brought it up now, okay, in case there are any networking uber lords there rolling their eyes here
like I don't know what it is, 10 minutes into the course and saying, oh this joker hasn't got a clue,
doesn't even know what a publically routable network address is.
Well stick with me okay. Anyway, back to the script, right. Availability zone, oh no wait, actually
if you're in the wrong region, now's the time to change that. VPCs, okay, are per region.
So an entire VPC exists inside of one region and only one region.
I'm an island here, okay, or a EU West as it's also known, and that's cool for me.
You can be in whatever region suits you. Anyway, back down here, we've got all of the availability zones
that are available, availability zones available, I like that, in whatever region you happen to be working in.
For now, I'm just going to go with 1B, just because it's in the middle.
It doesn't really matter for now. Then on the subnet name I'm going to go pub-podcast.
Now I definitely recommend naming your subnet and to be honest, you should name everything that you can in AWS,
unless of course you like the kind of long cryptic names that AWS assigns resources.
Take away point here, just name your stuff, okay.