Okay, so we've got two VPCs, more actually, but for this demo we've got our podcast VPC that we've been using
throughout the course, yeah, and I've created another one called blog.
I don't know, blogs and podcasts, yeah, only our blog VPC here belongs to one of my other AWS accounts.
One can never have too many AWS accounts, seriously. So yeah, it's absolutely possible to configure
peering connections between VPCs owned by different AWS accounts, they've just got to be in the same region, right.
Now over here in the podcast VPC, we've got a Linux instance in a public subnet and at the start of the demo
we're going to set it up pinging another instance over here in a private subnet in the blog VPC.
And at first, right, because this old boy over here has only got a private IP, it's going to fail,
get no replies. But then from over here, we're going to create a peering request and to do that we need
the AWS account ID that owns the remote VPC plus the ID of the VPC that we want to peer up with.
And of course, I've got things rigged up so that they're both in the eu-west region and I've got totally separate
CIDR blocks. Anyway, once that connection request is made it's going to pop up in this VPC dashboard over here.
Once we approve that, it'll trigger the creation of our peering connection objects.
Then all we need to do is update our routing tables. Now then, this bit like totally depends on how you've got
your routing set up. We've got it set up so that each VPC has got a couple of custom routing tables,
one of them is attached to all public subnets where the route to the internet and all and the other
is attached to all the private subnets, no route to the internet.
So what we're going to do in our podcast VPC is add a route to the route table attached to the public subnet
and if you can see that, which oh my goodness if you can, hello superman vision, for the rest of us though
it's basically the network of the remote blog VPC and a target of the new peering connection object.
Then over on this side we do the same, only this time for a private subnet, adding the network of the podcast VPC
back over here and a target of the same connection object, which for the record is named the same on both ends.
Then, if all goes to plan, we'll pull up that pinging Linux instance right before we save those final
routing changes and we should see the ping springing to life. So that's the plan.
Who's excited? I am. Let's go and do it.