Sticking with the theory for just a bit longer. Probably the first thing to say is that all instances
need a security group. It's a bit like a tax code, right, you've just got to have one though and like tax codes,
security groups are a good thing. In fact actually, instances are not limited to having just a single
security group, they can have more, up to five actually. Though, there is a subtly there.
Technically speaking, right, security groups actually get assigned to NICs, network interfaces on our instances
and not the instances themselves. So, me saying each instance can have up to five security groups
associated with it, well that's really five per network interface.
So an instance with 2 network interfaces, well it can obviously have 10 security groups, 3 network interfaces
that would be 15, yeah. Now then, and maybe we'll see this in a demo in a sec, but when we associate
a security group with an instance or when we think we're associating it with an instance, so we click the instance
in the EC2 console and we modify its security groups, we're actually working with the Eth0 NIC, the first NIC
in the instance and I don't want to get like massively side tracked by this, okay, because for all intents
and purposes we are associating with the instance because we can't remove the Eth0 network interface
from an instance. Now as much as I don't want us to get side tracked by this, I do think it's worth knowing,
so security groups are actually associated with network interfaces on an instance and not directly with
the instance itself and I'll try and show that when we come to the demo in a sec, right.
Now though, for how they actually work. So they're pretty much personal firewalls for our instances.
They allow or deny traffic. Okay, that's only like half true, okay.
What am I saying? Well, security groups, okay, can only actually be configured to allow traffic,
so we can only create rules that say things like, yeah allow this traffic or yes allow that traffic,
we can't explicitly say deny this traffic or deny that traffic. But okay, in reality if we don't specifically
allow a type of traffic, then it's going to get denied. So, once we create a security group and start populating it
with rules to allow traffic, any traffic then, I suppose we could say, whose name isn't on the list,
gets denied, yeah. So we create explicit allow rules and then anything not explicitly allowed is
implicitly denied. I'm much more of a fan of the practical then the theory.
Anyway, they pretty much look like this, well, they actually totally look like this because this is just
a screen shot. First up though, they can allow inbound and outbound traffic.
Inbound being traffic that's coming into our instance and outbound being traffic that's leaving the instance.
Then, for each we create a list of rules, each rule being a protocol, a port, and then depending on whether
it's inbound or outbound, it needs a source or a destination. So looking at the first line here,
this one's nice and easy, it's allowing unencrypted web traffic from any source.
Okay, well, how do I know that? Well by convention, unencrypted web traffic operates over TCP port 80
and by specifying 0.0.0.0/0 as the source, we're saying allow this traffic from any source, so a pretty
standard rule, yeah, one that you might legitimately apply to internet facing web servers.
The HTTP bit over here, we'll see this in the demo as well, but it's just a convenient way for us to pick
a predefined rule from a drop down list. The actual substance of the rule is these three columns here.
The rule down at the bottom here, it's pretty much the same, only this time it's allowing encrypted web traffic.
Then there's this bad boy in the middle. This guy is going to allow Docker traffic over TCP port 2375,
but only from devices in the 10.0.3 network. And the way this all works, right, is that when evaluating
traffic, right, so anytime traffic comes in, all rules get processed and checked, then if when we've processed
all the rules and we've not found a match, the traffic gets dropped, denied.
And outbound looks the same. Okay, a different rule, yeah, but the structure is the same, protocol,
port or port group, yeah, and a destination this time instead of a source.
Okay, now a few final things, we say that security groups are stateful, they act like a stateful firewall,
so for example, any responses to traffic that we send out are automatically allowed back in.
Think of it maybe like this, the security group, I guess we could say, remembers hey yeah, I allowed that
traffic out before and I can see that this is a legit response, so I'm going to let it back in.
And vice versa too, so if it's just allowed some traffic in via an inbound rule this time, it's going to
remember that too and it's going to let responses back out even if there's no explicit outbound rule saying so.
So security groups are of a sort stateful firewalls. Also, right, if you modify a security group,
so maybe add or remove a rule, no probs, it gets automatically applied and becomes effective on any instance
that the security group is associated with. It's totally dynamic, so on the fly, yeah, while the instances
are hot. A couple of final points, right, before we roll our sleeves up and get working.
We can have 100 security groups per region and each security group can have 50 rules.
Oh, and they don't filter traffic, okay, from the reserved addresses in your subnet.
So I think we mentioned this earlier, but every subnet's got 5 reserved addresses, the first 4 addresses
in the subnet and the last address in the subnet and these get used for DNS, DHCP, EC2 metadata,
key management server, and routing. That was a lot. I'm hoping that's us done with the theory,
let's jump on over to the console and see it in action.