Now if we scroll over to the right here,
I want to point this out first, the VPC that we just created is not a default VPC and there's actually no way
that we can make it a default VPC. Well, at least there's not at the time of recording, right.
Now what this basically means is if we want to launch instances into our new VPC, we've got to manually select it
when launching the instance. In fact, let me just show you (Loading).
Ubuntu, okay, right. See here, a new instance is automatically going to get launched into the region's
default VPC, they call it network over here, yeah, but really they're named VPC.
Well, I guess VPC basically is a network. But the point is, if we want to launch the instance into our VPC,
then we need to manually go in here and pick it from the drop down.
We don't want to bother doing that right now though. Back to VPCs, what else about default?
Yeah, I think we already said, every region's got one default VPC and that gets automatically created
for us by AWS and there's no way to change that. So even if we delete it, which we absolutely can,
well then our region just ends up with no default VPC. Then later on if we suddenly decide, uh that was a mistake
and we really do want one, well we need to go with our begging bowl and go and beg to Amazon to recreate it for us.
And you know what? It's been like this since like forever, since VPCs came along in fact.
And I'm pretty staggered to be honest that it's not changed yet. I mean, maybe by the time you're watching it
it has, but right now, like summer 2015, that's the crack. We can't set a VPC to be a default, so I'd probably
say, right, just leave the default VPC in each region alone. We're certainly not going to use them in this course.
Okay, but if we look down here, right, it's easy to read a summary of our new VPC.