So let's hit our public subnet and let's add some internet gateway action to its route table.
Ah, right, see how it's currently using the podcast local-RT route table, in fact, yeah, it's associated with
two subnets, so our public and our private subnets. What we want to do then is create a new route table.
And we'll call this one podcast-public-RT and what we'll do is we'll use this one for any subnets that need
access to the internet and we'll keep the local one for private subnets that don't need hooking directly up
to the internet. Okay so associated with our VPC (Loading), and I think first up, yeah, we'll add a new route first.
Now the easiest way to add a route pointing to our internet gateway is to add a default route like this.
So that's what all of those zeros is, a catchall route that will get taken if there's not a more specific route.
A bit like auto's directions if you've ever driven in France, which I'm sure most of you probably haven't,
so I don't know why I'm saying it. The point being though, when an instance comes to send packets to a destination,
and this is the high level, right, it looks at the route table and it says, okay which route do I need to take?
If there's a match on the route table it sends the packets to whatever is listed in the target here,
but if there's no match then it sends data to whatever's listed as the target for the 0.0.0.0/0 default route,
kind of if there aren't any matches then send it this way, the all other routes or all other directions
that you often get on road signs. So, all these zeros represents our all other destinations default route.
So, we want to point this to the internet gateway and see how it suggests that for us and it even includes
our friendly name that we gave it, cool. And that's pretty much it.
That's our road sign right there. Local traffic, so anything that matches our 10.0 network, hit the local route.
Anything and everything else, head for the internet gateway. Magic, super simple.
But let's just take a step back for a sec and draw this out because I'm aware that I've maybe waffled a bit
and I might have distracted you.
So we've created an internet gateway for our VPC, that superman style internet gateway to end all
internet gateways. Well, that's our road or our route to the internet.
Then, inside our public subnet we updated the road signs. We created a route table entry that said, hey
for anything that you don't see above, so anything that doesn't match our 10.0 network, head over to the
internet gateway. But we only added that rule to the route table of our public subnet.
Our private subnet still knows nothing about it. Not hard at all, right?
Now hopefully not flogging a dead horse here, but how this routing table stuff works is the most specific routes
get precedence over the less specific ones. Any by specific I suppose I mean the subnet mask bit, right.
So let's say we had two routes that were similar, 10.0.0.0/16 and 10.0.0.0/24.
Well the /24 route is the most specific because it includes more bits in the mask, 24 rather than 16, right.
Well what this means, our default route here is as unspecific as it gets, right.
So that route is only ever going to get picked if there's literally nothing else that even comes close to matching.
Good stuff and all and it really is, but even that's not enough to give our instances direct access to the internet.
We've one more thing to configure, public IPs.