Well when Amazon was first launched, like back in the mid 2000s, there was just the S3 object store
and the EC2 virtual machine platform and it's like, oh yeah. As it was, it was just too little for a lot
of potential customers, especially, right, established businesses and enterprises.
You see, most established companies were used to their own data centers
where they owned the service, storage, and networking and they were in full control of the lot.
Then enter EC2 as a virtual machine computing platform and suddenly not only were the servers and the likes
not theirs, but they had precious little control over them too, especially in the networking space.
So it was like, spin up an EC2 instance, a virtual machine, yeah, question, what's it's IP address going to be?
Answer, uh, well, look that's just not a good answer okay. So very cool, yeah.
Lots of shortcomings also, yeah. Well here entereth VPCs. These let us build pretty much our own virtual
data center in AWS and we'll see all of this in just a sec, right.
But for instance, we get to choose the network range for our entire VPC and then we're free to carve that up
into as many subnets as we want. But not only that, we can put these subnets in whichever availability zones
we want and that is massive, right. It means we can say things like, okay I want a couple of web servers
for performance and availability and then choose to deploy one into a subnet that let's say in availability zone
1A and the other into a subnet that's in availability zone 1B. Then if 1A goes away, so like the whole
availability zone or maybe just the EC2 service, yeah, who cares, we're cool.
1B is still up and we're still in business. But it's not just that, on each of these subnets, we can lash
network access control lists just like we do on routers and firewalls in our corporate data center networks
and before long, this is starting to look a whole lot like a regular corporate or data center network,
which is a huge driver for adoption. You see, by making a VPC look and feel a lot like a traditional network
a bunch more customers are going to deploy it. Now I don't want to waffle, I really want to get cracking
and show you, but just maybe 1 more minute of your time, okay, before we get into it, I want to give you
a couple of warnings.