First up, right this stuff is addictive. So beware of the drug dealer model and I'm not making light of
drug dealing here, nor am I calling Amazon drug dealers, I'm just trying to warn you, as is often the case
with drug dealers, the first hit is free, then once you're hooked that's when it starts to cost
and genuinely best of luck pulling yourself free. Well the same can potentially happen with AWS.
Initial upfront costs can be so low as to be almost insignificant, but then if you're not careful
before you know it, you're going to find yourself running a shed load of stuff on there and that's when
you're going to start to feel the cost.
Also, man, be careful not to do a Code Spaces. So if you don't know, there was this company called Code Spaces
that I think was essentially a cloud based version control system or something like that, and like a lot
of startups, they built their infrastructure, an entire business actually, on AWS.
The problem being, actually, I should be careful about pointing the blame here, but the issue okay,
was they were hosting everything on AWS, so their production environment and all its backups.
Okay, I get that, it makes life easy, yeah. A single AWS account and you've got access to everything,
makes day to day ops nice and easy, right. Though, I'm sure you've probably twigged, it also makes it
dead, dead simple to trash the entire thing. So in the case of Code Spaces, someone malicious got access
to that AWS account, it doesn't matter who, right, could be a disgruntled employee, an external hacker,
whatever, right. The point is, they gained access to the Code Spaces AWS account and well, basically deleted
the company production services and all of its backups. Yeah, not a great story.
And don't get me wrong, okay, multifactor authentication, separate accounts for different roles,
proper identity and access management, maybe even hosting backups or copies of backups elsewhere.
There are a ton of things that can be done to mitigate disasters like this and in truth, it's not massively
different to any other cloud providers or even on-prem non-cloud solutions where you have your own kit
and your own data center. You can still totally be hacked and owned or have a disgruntled employee wreak havoc.
Whatever the case, right, do everything necessary to mitigate your risk, it's your responsibility.
Anyway, on that chirpy note, should we have some fun building a VPC?
Hmm, not so easy to sound excited after that. But don't worry, no, no actually do worry, care about security,
lock things down, spread your risk, all of that jazz. And if you do, you'll be able to sleep at night
and we'll be able to rock and roll with the rest of this course.
So let's do that, yeah, I feel better already. So next on the card, okay, we're going to build a VPC
with the wizard. A quick module to paint the big VPC picture. And don't worry if you hate wizards, like me,
once we've done this we're going to build it all again but without the wizard.
Let's go and have some VPC fun.