Right. Let's build this load balancer. So we want to be down here, huh, alright, well it used to be,
I'm pretty sure, under Network and Security. Now I wonder if they've got plans to expand load balancing
possibilities, you know, given it its own section and whatever. Anyway, let's hope they've not changed
a bunch else, otherwise this could be interesting, but we'll go and create a new one.
Looks normal. First up, the usual name and VPC stuff. We'll call our podcast-ELB-internet so that we know
it's internet facing and not internal. Obviously we'll stick it in our podcast VPC, ah, right,
see how the screen changed? Because we selected our podcast VPC, which is not a default VPC, yeah.
Well this advanced config box here got automatically checked. Anyway, back up here, right, if we wanted to
create an internal load balancer, so for one that would load balance traffic from within our VPC
instead of from the internet, well we'd hit this. But we're going to go internet facing this time.
And then for the listener config. This is where we tell our load balancer which port to listen on
and which port to forward to instances on. Now then, the current config of listening for incoming HTTP requests
on port 80 here and then passing them on internally on the same port, this is actually exactly what we want.
But a common and a pretty useful config, right, can be to listen here on HTTPS, so encrypted web traffic,
and then pass on internally a straight HTTP. What this does, right, is it lets us use and abuse the load balancer
to terminate our HTTPS sessions and as a result take some of the load off our instances.
I don't know, it might be useful for you. But see as well, right, how we can't configure our elastic
load balancer for that many protocols. Like I think we said earlier, while it is the absolute bizzo and all,
it's not the most comprehensive load balancer that you can find.
Other load balancers are available. Anyway this is good for us, okay.
It's going to receive web traffic and then balance that traffic over the instances that we configure behind it.
Now for subnets, see this nice little message here, balance over multiple subnets where possible folks,
that's where the app high availability comes from. Well, we'll pick both of our public facing subnets,
and you know what? The eu-west region has got three availability zones actually and there's absolutely nothing
stopping us balancing over all three, obviously we need subnets in all three, right.
And you know? That would actually give us even better availability than just balancing over two.
The only reason I'm not going to do that here is honestly, right, because the diagrams that I'm using on the slides
they started to looking really busy when I started trying to fit three availability zones on them.
So, two is no magic number or anything like that.
Next, now then, for security group, we're going to go with this HTTP only one that we created a minute or two ago.
We're not bothered about this message, we know that HTTP is just plain text.
I do recommend HTTPS for production, of course. Now health checks, and these are the chiz-zing, right.
These three bits up here, they form like the basics or the meat of our health check, yeah.
So this particular one is going to send an HTTP request on port 80 and if index.html exists,
then the health check is a pass. If there's no response or index.html doesn't exist, it's going to fail.
And we can edit these fields as well, right, though the top one here can only be one of these options.
But these old boys down here, well health check interval here, right, this is how many seconds we wait
between health checks, so between the pings that we defined up here.
And then the healthy threshold down here, 10, well what we're going to need then is 10 successful pings
or health checks before we consider the instance healthy, and you know what?
Instances have got to be considered healthy before they get thrown into a load balancer config,
which brings a good point actually, all of these health checks here apply to instances, right.
But you know what? 10 checks with a 30 second interval between each one, that's like 5 minutes, right,
and not even counting the time it takes to perform the check. Either way, right, that's an absolute age.
Meaning that any new instances that we add behind this load balancer, it's going to be a long and painful
5 minutes before they get added into the mix. So what I'm going to do is I'm going to make this 2 checks
at 10 second intervals, which is better, for me at least, right.
But you probably want to give this some thought because we probably don't want to be throwing recovering instances
straight back into the mix, we probably want to give them a chance to see if they're going to stick around first
before giving them work to do. And it's similar for marking instances as unhealthy, taking them out of the game,
yeah. We're 2 checks here at a 10 second interval again, so 20 seconds before we say, you're out, on the sideline.
And last but not least, response time here, that's like how long do we wait to hear back before we consider
the ping up there failed? And wowsers, 5 seconds is long, right?
Not even in the days of 56K dial-up modems was like 5 seconds considered reasonable.
But you know what, I'm going to leave it for now. Now to add some instances.
Well we've got two and we'll have them both thanks. Basically here just telling a load balancer when
you receive this web traffic, go and load balance it over these two instances.
And yes thanks, we'd like cross-zone load balancing. What this does is, okay, it makes sure that all instances
get a fair share of the work. So imagine, right, if we had two instances in one availability zone,
and only one instance in the other availability zone, well all three instances would get a third of the work
if we've got this checkbox checked, checkbox checked. And that's despite the fact, right, that there's
only two availability zones. Effectively, what it's saying is, when it comes to load balancing, right,
don't really worry about the availability zones, just think about the instances and balance evenly across
the instances. I'm a fan of this option anyway. Last option, right, enable connection draining 300 seconds,
so 5 minutes again. Well this is kind of an important little setting.
It lets us say, hey when we come to take an instance out of the config, so maybe de-register it, yeah,
well once we've done that, let it stick around a bit for this time here so that any potentially active sessions
to it get a chance to finish and whether or not this number should be big or small is totally dependent
on your application's requirements. So do your clients care if they get kicked off an active session?
And you know what? Will the app have to start again if that happens?
Who knows, right, it depends on your application. The point is, the option is there.
We're not bothered about any tags, so let's create this thing. Right.
And there it is, okay. Status of our instances down here, remember they're having their health checks performed
right now so it's going to be something like about 20 seconds before they're up and in the game.
So if we come up and we refresh the browser here (Loading), nope still not in service yet.
Let's give that another try. Right, both in service. And we can scroll down further and see other options.
Now stickiness here, this one's new to us. But all it is is session affinity with cookies, if we enable it
browser's are going to get a cookie that tells the load balancer to direct future sessions back to the same instance
on the back end. There's more access logs and idle timeout as well.
We can go and configure those. But you know what? That's our elastic load balancer, honestly,
all up and configured. And in the grand scheme of things, how easy was that?
I mean, knowing how to do that ain't going to make you skilled enough and important enough to be able to
arrive at a customer site dressed in a shell suit, no, but who cares about that, it sure as hell
could make your app higher performing and way more resilient. So let's go and see it in action.