So we've got all of the VPC and subnetty type infrastructure in place to get us out onto the internet,
but in order for any instances to actually make it out there, they need a public IP and I know it's probably
not needed, but just in case, okay. Let's build out our analogy of roads and road signs.
So if our routers and internet gateways are our actual roads, and our route table entries are like our road signs,
then public IPs, I suppose, are a bit like cars. You're with me, right?
In order to get out there on the internet or onto the motorway or highway, yeah, our instance needs a public IP
or a car. Just like you can't take a bike on the motorway, like a pedal bike, yeah, well at least in England
you can't, well you can't take a private IP onto the internet, you need a public one.
Okay, well, we have a couple of ways to accomplish that. We can either assign an instance of public IP
when we create the instance or we can set an attribute on the subnet so that every time we launch an instance
into that subnet it's going to get one automatically. Right, so if we head over to our public subnet
and then see here in the Summary tab of it, and in fact look, it's the same for any subnet, right,
or at least we've got this setting in every subnet. Auto-assign public IP, well we need to set that to yes.
And there's the option right there or up here in Subnet Actions. And again, look, it couldn't be any simpler,
one tick in the box and we're in business. Though, I will point out, right, we've no way of controlling
what IP address gets assigned. Sure it'll be publically routable, but we don't get to choose what the actual
addresses are. Anyway, should we go and spin up an instance?