Yes, my favorite bit, getting into the console and actually building stuff.
Anyway, so we've got two VPCs belonging to two different AWS accounts and the way that I normally roll with this
is I open them in two separate browsers, one account in Chrome and the other in Firefox.
It just means that Chrome saves my creds for one account and Firefox for the other.
So, in Chrome first, we've got our podcast VPC, nice and familiar, yeah.
And we should have a single running instance (Loading), yeah, and with a public IP and DNS name.
In fact, let's grab that DNS name and I'll open up an SSH session to it, by magic, yeah.
Okay, so ip a, so 10.0.1.250 and yes, it's the right box. Remember okay, instances don't know about their
public IPs, that's all mapped in a table on the internet gateway.
Never mind that though, if we scoot quickly over to Firefox to our other account, okay, two more VPCs.
And this blog one is the one that we care about. But for now, right, we want to grab the private IP
of the instance that we're going to try and ping. Okay. And it's going to be this one here, blog and then
in the private subnet and it's a Linux box. And this is it's private IP, so if we grab that, then go and try
and ping it (Typing). Yeah, not looking good. Nope, definitely no replies coming back.
Okay, back to Firefox. What we want now is some VPC ID stuff and the likes (Typing).
So this is our blog VPC ID here, same again down here, and here, oh and notice it's CIDR block, yeah,
in the 172 range. But we'll have a copy of this and we'll keep it in here.
Remember, this is the ID of the VPC that we're going to request a connection to.
Also, right, we're going to want the ID of the account here that owns it and, by the way, don't be thinking
because it says Nigel Poulton here and it's the same back here in Chrome, these are just display names,
they are totally different accounts. Anyway, if we click the dropdown and my account, this is what we want.
No offense, I love you guys and all, but you never know who's watching, so I'm going to hide my personal details,
yeah, in fact by the time you're watching this they'll already be hidden.
But let's paste this into here, okay, so we're ready to rock and roll creating this peering request,
so from our podcast VPC, I'm sorry for all the jumping back and forth here, you're probably getting sea sick,
I know, but we're back in our podcast VPC. And if we hit peering connections here, don't worry about this
deleted one, we want the big blue button here, Create VPC Peering Connection.
And by now, right, we know all about the importance of naming our stuff.
So we'll call this I think podcast <> blog and pick our podcast VPC from here.
Now then, we can obviously created a connection between two VPCs that our account here owns, or we can
lash up a connection to a VPC owned by another account. Well, that's what we want.
Okay, we'll grab the account ID (Typing) and the VPC ID (Typing).
Alright then, so we've got a nice meaningful name. We're going to go from our podcast VPC here to this VPC ID
here owned by this AWS account. Let's do it. Now then, at this point it's probably important to remember
that this is only going to work, right, if our two VPCs are in the same region and if they don't have
overlapping CIDR blocks, right. Anyway, take a note of the status here, pending, and that's acceptance,
which is good, it means if we jump back over to our other account, navigate back to our VPC dashboard,
peering connections, there we go. Now then, I'm expecting this, right, but you totally want to make sure, right,
that all this stuff, like Account ID and maybe VPC ID, that they all match up with what you're expecting.
Never just blinded accept peering requests. Then all we need to do now is hit Accept request down,
one final chance to double check everything, and there we go, all established.
And if we come back here, where is it? Yeah, this ID here, this pcx object, this is our peering connection object,
so like an internet gateway, yeah. This is going to be our target when we update our routing tables.
Speaking of which, let's go and do it.