So to rock and roll with VPN connections, we want to be over here in our VPC dashboard.
And then down here under VPN Connections. And we'll just go through the three in order from top to bottom.
So Customer Gateways here, this is our end of the tunnel, yeah, and we don't currently have any.
But I want to point this out, okay, customer gateway config is really two things.
There's the actual gateway itself, okay, so the piece of kit that we own on our office premises,
that hardware device that we talked about that's our end of the tunnel.
Well as well as that, then there's the corresponding object in AWS and that's what we're configuring here, okay.
And this object, right, it's just a way for us to tell AWS a bit about our actual physical gateway.
So if we take a look here, right, so name, routing, and IP address.
The name's arbitrary, right, so we'll go with something that fits our loose standard, yeah.
And then the routing and IP bits, they're just our way of telling AWS a little bit about the config
on our end of the tunnel. The IP address at the bottom here, this is the public IP address of our router
or our VPN endpoint, that static IP address that we were just talking about.
So, if my office's public IP address is 94.119.64.23, then that's what I put in here.
It's just the public interface of the piece of hardware I've got on my end of the tunnel.
And remember, make it static, okay, because it's just not feasible to be changing this thing.
Remember, we want this VPN connection to be always up and reliable.
Anyway, then for the routing, okay, we've got a couple of options, static and dynamic.
So, static is a bit like the cheap and cheerful option, it's nice and easy to configure, right,
but it doesn't scale well. We've got to do things like manually add routes on both ends and it's great and all,
but it becomes hard work at any kind of scale. Dynamic on the other hand, this is the more
I suppose enterprise-y option. It uses BGP, the border gateway protocol, and it doesn't need static routes
entering. Instead, both ends of the tunnel, so obviously both ends need to support it, yeah,
but both ends they advertise routes to each other and it scales like a lizard.
The downside being, you need to be a bit of a network ninja to configure it.
Now I'm no networking ninja, so I'm all over the static option. Then we click Create.
And that's our customer gateway object all configured. Next, we want the AWS and the virtual private gateway.
Again, we've not got any, so we'll create one. And look at that.
Just a single option to configure, name tag, talk about easy. Well, we'll be boring and go with podcast-vgw01
and there we go. So we've got our end of the tunnel here, podcast-cgw01, it's available, IPsec,
it's IP address, and because we went with static routing we could ignore this BGP autonomous system
number thing here. Back over here on the AWS end, and the same again, IPsec, but not attached to a VPC yet.
So let's attach it (Typing) and there we go. With both ends configured, that means all we need to do now
is stitch them together. So that'll be VPN connections and Create.
Okay, so this time a little bit more to do. We'll go podcast-vpn for the name.
Yes this is our virtual private gateway here, dead simple as we've only got one, but remember, right,
naming stuff properly comes into its own when we've got like a boatload of everything.
Oh and they can be useful for billing as well, yeah. We'll go with our existing customer gateway
we just configured, though if we click New, yeah, we totally can create a new one right here right now,
but we've already got one and we're definitely in the static camp here, yeah.
Okay, now in this box we put in the networks that we want to be reachable over this connection.
So, our office network, we said that was 10.1.0.0/16 and we're ready to go.
Now in the real world, right, you might have a bunch of networks that you want to reach over this connection,
well that's just fine. You can list pretty much as many as you want here, just separate them with commas,
yeah like this. Anyway, we'll just go with the one. Create (Loading), okay that's having a good old think,
come on Amazon, it's like we're installing Windows for work groups with like 14 floppies or whatever it was,
we don't expect this kind of hanging around in the cloud area now.
Maybe I'll pause the video here, okay, it's back, there it is, right.
Though it's not available just yet. Now, here's the config down here, so both ends of the connection, yeah,
the type and the networking wimp's option of static routing. If we hit Tunnel Details, we can see both endpoints.
Remember we said earlier that we automatically get this highly available design, so two tunnels,
each with its own IP, and each currently down. But the point being, if we connect our end up to both of these,
if one goes down the tunnel itself stays up. Good stuff, it's just down right now, okay, because we haven't
configured the actual router on our end. So to configure our router, we hit the Download Config up here,
then depending on our router make and model, yeah, I mean who even knew that Yamaha made routers?
I thought they made like pianos and motorbikes. Anyway, if your kit is on the list here, just select the model
and then the software version and hit Download and what you'll get is a nice text file with all the commands
and config stuff that you need to put into your router. It's really simple actually, but if your kit ain't
on the list, then you're going to want to go with generic here and what that's going to give you
is a nice little file that explains all the settings that you need to set, you just don't get the actual
commands this time around, you're going to have to work them out for yourself, but it's pretty easy.
Now then, here's where like I totally, totally let you know. Wait, no.
What? Don't press Cancel. You just pressed Cancel, why? Okay, so I'm like kicking back in the home office
here, yeah, and not being a networking guy, sorry, I don't have a router here at my end of the tunnel.
So sorry folks, I can't complete the demo for you, but you know what, don't hate me.
That part of the config is totally like non-AWS stuff, it's proper Cisco or Juniper or even Yamaha, yeah.
Seriously we've done all the AWS config and learning, the only thing left to do is configure your router
with the config that you downloaded from the previous step. Once that's done your tunnel is going to come up
and as long as you configure keep-alives or you keep traffic going across it, it's going to stay up.
Pretty cool stuff. Oh, to bring it up in the first place as well, actually, you need to send traffic
from your end, so it is actually our end of the tunnel, right, that's responsible for bringing it up
and sending any necessary keep-alives that might be needed to keep it up and healthy.
But that's how we configure a site to site VPN in AWS. Time for one more VPN related topic before we wrap up
the module.