Now then, private subnet.
Again, we see that the network address that we've chosen is, wait for it, a subnet or a sub network
or a slice of the wider address range up here in the VPC network, but it is slightly different to the public subnet
we just created. So we're kind of saying, hey we're in the city called 10.1, we take that from our VPC definition
at the top, and our public subnet is on a street called 0 and our private subnet a street called 1.
Then any devices that we put into these subnets, so containers and EC2 instances, they get house numbers
in the last octet after the final period, yeah. Does that make sense?
It does for me at least. Anyway, for now we'll stick it in the same availability zone and we'll call it
priv-podcast. Easy, right? This is a breeze. Now the NAT instance here, this is basically a specialized
EC2 instance that's going to live in our public subnet, but it lets instances in our private subnet
talk to the wider world, the internet. Now real quick, okay, it works by getting itself a public IP address,
so not a 10. address, yeah, that means it can talk directly with the internet, and then we just create a route
in our private network that says, hey you know what, for any traffic whose IP address we don't know where
to send it to, send it over to the NAT instance. The NAT instance then does some networking magic, there I go
with magic again, but anyway, it does some networking magic so that that traffic gets sent over to the internet.
Any replies, well they get routed back to the appropriate host on the private subnet.
Simple, though like in everything, right, there's a bunch more to it than that and we're going to cover it
all in due time. I just thought, right, you might like to know the basics of how it works for the time being.
Okay, we need to choose an instance type here for our NAT. Now I'm not going to be pushing this hard
in the lab at all, plus I'm a cheapskate, so I'll go with m1 small.
You go with whatever you think you're going to need for your requirements, but if you're just following along
or playing in the lab, you're probably going to be fine with just an m1 small and charges to apply here, okay.
Oh, for a keeper here, well I'm going to go with podcast-keys that I created earlier.
But you know what? I could choose any of my available keys, right, as long as I'm in possession of them.
But I just like to keep things neat and tidy, so I'm going to go with the pair that I created with a
meaningful name, now I'm not bothered about S3 endpoints for now, but yeah I do want to enable DNS host names.
What this is going to do is just make sure that any instances that we spin up in this VPC, okay, are going to get
DNS names that are resolvable internally within AWS and externally on the public internet, the latter of course
only being if we're putting them in a public subnet and giving them public IPs, but the idea is, right,
if we want name resolution rather than just working with IP addresses, we want to say yes to this.
And last but not least here, this hardware tenancy option, this lets up change from the default of where
we share actual server hardware and the likes with other folks, to the other option, dedicated where we
pay for dedicated physical servers that we don't share with anyone else.
But that's going to cost a ton more than the default shared tenancy.
Anyway, it all looks good to me, let's create it. And off it goes.