Right then, from within our VPC console, Security Groups is down here under Security.
You can get to it from the EC2 dashboard as well, but if we hit it here we see our existing security groups,
ah, none of which are named. Slap across the face for me for laziness.
But here we go, okay, right. Name tag here is the friendly name that it's going to get.
We'll go with podcast Docker Hosts and we don't like ugly red text, so we've got to give it a description (Typing).
That'll do. Obviously we're going to want our podcast VPC and there it goes, creating it for us.
Or actually, it's creating an empty shell for us. So if we see down here, yeah, currently no inbound rules,
so nothing has been allowed in yet, but everything is being allowed out.
So back here we're going to add a rule to allow TCP port 2375. Right, good.
I might have forgot that. I'm going to put in a CIDR block here, but as we can see, we can totally pick
another security group if we want. Pretty much that would be saying allow TCP 2375 access from any host
that happens to be a member of whichever of these security groups we choose.
Nifty and all, but we'll go with 10.0.2.0/24. Restricting access, yeah, to instances in our private subnet.
And let's do another one. Call this one podcast web traffic, copy and paste that down here, choose our VPC,
and off we go again (Loading). This time, okay, we'll add HTTP and HTTPS and we'll do both of them
from anywhere (Typing). Okay, so there we go, right. Two new security groups, each with some inbound rules
and both, right, allowing all outbound traffic. Not the most secure in the world, this outbound bit here,
I know, but you know what? It's not uncommon either. Now if we jump over to our EC2 console,
and what have we got here? Hmm, not a lot really, especially in our podcast VPC.
So let's go fire another one up. This'll do, yep, podcast VPC, public subnet, yeah it's going to get a public IP,
storage is good, podcast-test is good. Ah, now if we click up here, right, see how we can select from existing
security groups? Lovely and all, but this time we're going to let the wizard create one for us.
Now by default, okay, with this being a Linux instance, it's only going to allow SSH traffic in.
So that's just the bare minimum, right, so that we can get in and manage our instance.
And note the name and the description here, if we're not careful, right, we can end up with an absolute
rats nest of security groups that are named like this. Anyway we'll go kick it off (Typing), uh huh.
Now while it's firing up, okay, why don't we go and give it an elastic IP from over here.
Okay, just got the one for right now. Let's associate it. We'll pick our instance from here, hmm,
I wonder, maybe it's just spinning up, yeah, we'll give it a chance to spin up, right.
These virtual machines, you know, they're not like containers, spin up times can feel like eons if you're
getting used to containers. Okay, there it is now and that'll do.
If we go back here, there we go, elastic IP. Now then, right now it's just got the one security group, yeah.
The one we created when launching the instance to allow SSH. So let's grab its public IP here,
let's go fire up a session. Okay, we'll give it our private key, and yep we'll make the font a decent size.
Okay, let's go. Drag it over here and we're in. So let's just take a step back for a second and take stock
real quick. We've just SSH'ed in using the instance's public IP or its elastic IP and we're only being allowed in
because the security group associated with the instance is allowing SSH traffic from anywhere.
Magic. Well, let's switch to route and we'll update our repos (Typing).
Okay, let me speed up time while that happens. Okay. Now we'll install the Apache web server (Typing).
Great, is that running? Nope. So let's go start it. Good. Right.
So the instance is now running the Apache web server. But obviously if we go try to connect to it
over here, give it a second or so, dah-dah-dah, no joy. Reason, its security group is dropping any packets
that are not SSH. So to fix that, we'll we need to either edit the security group so that it's got a
rule in that allows web traffic or we can add another security group that's already got a rule allowing web traffic.
Well, we'll do the latter yeah, since we already created one of those groups just a second ago.
So if we right click it, Networking and Change Security Groups here, we want to add this podcast web traffic
one here, and notice as well, we could disassociate the launch wizard one while we're here if we wanted to,
but we don't. And look down here, see how we've got both security groups listed now?
And if we view the rules, yeah, it shows us a pretty nice combo of the two.
So if we jump back here, try this again, bingo. Web traffic now allowed.
Totally dynamic, yeah, totally on the fly, and totally cool. So that's security groups, yeah.
Just one more quick thing, if you look under security groups here, yeah, we're actually not that bad,
I have seen this a royal mess in the past because it's so easy to spin up loads of instances without thinking of it
and each time let the wizard create a new security group for you.
You know what? Before you know it this screen is like littered with these launch wizard security groups,
I don't know like 20 or 30 of them, yeah. So name your security groups and keep on top of them
because they can be a proper pain to unpick. Oh yeah, I did say I'd show you how network interfaces
and security groups go together. Well let's jump over here, oh, where are they hiding?
There they are, whew, just a handful right now, one for each instance, yeah.
Though we can create more if we want to and then associate them with our instances, but we'll pick this one here.
And see how we've got that Change Security Groups option, there we go.
This is how we associate and disassociate security groups with network interfaces.
And that folks is security groups, totally cool and totally important.
But let's switch gears slightly now, let's go and look at a close cousin of the security group, network ACLs.