So, every VPC gets one of these crazy cryptic AWS names, but see how we can see the friendly name here as well?
Seriously, name your stuff or you're going to lose your mind. We've got state information, the network
that we assigned it, and then DHCP options set, this one's new to us.
Well, you know how, actually maybe you don't, okay, come on let's just back up a smidge.
I suppose, right, what DHCP is most famous for is dynamically assigning IP addresses to devices on a network,
so every machine on an IP network needs an IP address in order to communicate.
Well, instead of ours manually assigning every machine a unique address, most of the time we just conscript DHCP
into managing all of that for us. So we give DHCP a pool of IP addresses and pretty much say, hey
any time a new system appears on the network and asks for an address, go ahead and lease it one.
Bingo. And it takes care of a bunch of other stuff too like making sure that we don't assign the same address
to two devices and all of that jazz. And that's cool and all, but DHCP, oh, dynamic host configuration protocol,
in case you're wondering what it stands for, well it can assign a bunch more than just IP addresses.
So let' take a look at this options set, handy those little hyper links.
Well, we can see how this options set is also going to assign a domain name of eu-west-1.compute.internal
and it's going to tell the instances to use, well, as the name clearly suggests, Amazon's own DNS servers.
In fact, Amazon provided DNS is actually a DNS server that sits on the second address in your VPC's network,
so in our VPC with 10.0.0.0/16, it's going to be sitting on 10.0.0.2.
But I'm getting ahead of myself here, so we'll park that for now.
What I'm saying though is that DHCP options set let us do stuff like, well you know what, let's just go and see.
Okay, so we could say, well let's do this first. Okay, so we could say, intechwetrustpodcast.com,
so that all of our instances get a host name in the intechwetrustpodcast.com domain, try saying that.
We could point it to Google's famous DNS server and we can point it to an NTP server for accurate time too,
and I totally just made that address up, right. And seriously, right, if you need to configure nasty old
NetBIOS stuff, oh man, you really want to drag yourself out of the 90's.
So a bunch of stuff that they can manage and configure, okay, but it's worth knowing.
DHCP options sets are associated with your AWS account. So they're not limited to the scope of let's say
a VPC or a region or anything like that, no, and it's totally possible to have multiple sets of DHCP options set,
try saying that, good grief, but any VPC can only have one assigned to it.
So I can't assign two DHCP options sets to this new podcast VPC, but I totally can assign this single,
I'm just going to call it a set this time, to multiple VPCs. In fact, that's actually how I've got things now.
Hopefully that made sense, if it didn't, right, rewind about 30 seconds and listen to it again, if it still
doesn't make sense after that, then call me out on Twitter and we can chat about it live.
But for the crappy part, why oh why is there always a crappy part?
Even in like the awesome world of AWS there's still annoying stuff.
Though, I've got to be careful here, I could be totally wrong about this by the time that you're watching the course.
But at the time of recording, once you create a DHCP options set, you can't modify it.
In fact, look, there's no modify option, just delete. Alright, if we go back to our VPC again, oh yeah,
one more thing about DHCP options sets. I'm taking loads more time here on VPCs than I was expecting to.
If we change the DHCP options set that we've got associated with a VPC, we don't necessarily need to reboot
our instances. So what happens is, right, when an instance gets its IP config from a DHCP option set
it gets it on a lease and then every so often it needs to renew that lease.
Well, when that time comes to renew the lease, any instance is going to pick up the new options.
There we go, DHCP options sets. Now route table, just a quick and dirty for now, okay.
Route tables basically tell us how to navigate around our VPC and after the internet as well, which we'll see
in the next module. Think of them as kind of like maps or directions, yeah.
Then we've got network ACL, another one that we're going to cover later, but for now it's basically a list of what
traffic gets allowed and what traffic gets blocked. Tenancy, we already know about that.
And then finally, DNS resolution and DNS host names. Do we want our hosts to be able to look up DNS names
and resolve them to IP addresses? And then do we want instances in this VPC to get assigned DNS host names?
So map their IP addresses to friendlier, more readable DNS names?
Well, we want yes on both of these counts. So if we go up to Actions up here, Edit DNS Hostnames,
Yes, and Save. Wowzers! Finally, we can go and create some subnets.