Anybody else with a question? Yeah, good day mate. Brad here from Australia.
These security groups and network access control lists, they sound a bit similar, mate.
Which of the two should I be using? Hi Brad. Just real quick actually, did you by any chance see England
play Australia in the Ashes recently? That's cricket for anyone out there who doesn't know.
Anyway, the answer to that question is simple. Both. You should definitely use both.
And more, right. The idea being, there's no single technology that on its own is going to keep your
infrastructure safe. We really do need to deploy multiple layers of security, defense in-depth, yeah.
So we protected the subnet level with NACLs and we've protected the instance level with security groups.
Yeah, they might take a bit of learning and yeah, no doubt, they're going to be a bit of a pain at first,
in fact you're probably going to find yourself tripping over them from time to time, you know, like
you're going to be wondering something's not working or why you can't connect to an instance or something, yeah.
And it's going to turn out to be because of a NACL rule or a security group rule.
And you might even be tempted to turn the blasted things off. But don't.
Honestly, don't. They are proper insurance policies. And you know Murphy's law says that the day that you
cancel your home insurance your house is going to burn to the ground?
Well don't let the equivalent happen to your VPC. Get to know NACLs and get to know security groups
and use them properly. And this is a good idea s well, right, have some standards, yeah, and maybe document them
and who knows, even stick to them, yeah. Just so that you've got a bit of a pattern to how you use them,
and I'm talking simple things like what's your strategy for applying security groups, yeah?
Is it one per instance or one per instance type like web servers or one security group per application tier
or whatever, yeah? Just do it, right. I can't stress this enough.
Security is not optional anymore and NACLs and security groups really do complement each other.
So don't cheat and just try to use one. You know what, right, these are just the basics, the minimum, yeah.
You can totally use like third party tools as well, intrusion prevention systems, you can encrypt
bits and pieces, you might want to run antivirus, SC Linus, AppArmor.
There's tons of stuff. Take security seriously. But yeah, of the two major things that we've covered
in the course, NACLs and security groups, use them both and use them wisely.