Alright, so thanks to my insane ability to bend space time, the marvelous video editing, our VPC is
successfully created. But I kid you not here, okay, this is like one of the understatements of the technology era,
seriously. I mean I just can't overemphasize what we've just done here.
We should probably be running up and down the street naked, though obviously that's not an official
recommendation from Pluralsight, but do let me tell you why it's such an understatement.
We have literally built ourselves a world class data center here.
I just can't say it any other way. No word of a lie. I mean we've got, what have we got?
We've got world class physical data center facilities behind everything that we've just created, so stuff like
world class air con, world class power and power management, world class cabling, world class
internet access, you name it, the whole shebang is backed by Amazon's world class data center infrastructures.
It's not like you've just carved out for yourself some resources from the machines in my home lab,
no, no, no, you have got a virtual data center sitting on top of world class highly available physical infrastructure.
In fact I'm selling our achievement short, right? Depending on what your choices were when we were building
the VPC back there, you might well have built yourself two world class data centers and with high speed,
highly available links between them. This is seriously a monumental achievement.
And to make it even better, how much has it cost us so far? Zilch, nothing, well, okay so that NAT instance
is probably costing us a penny or so, right, but you grock, right.
We just built ourselves a world class data infrastructure in like a couple of minutes for an absolute steal
and we hardly had to know anything about data center design. I mean how is that possible?
I need to calm down, but it's pretty impressive in my book. I mean, I remember back in the day, right,
racking and stacking physical equipment, having contractors in to pull cabling, test AC equipment,
pulling up floor tiles, cutting my fingers and hands on like ridiculous server rails, and patching cables
behind a bunch of servers and switches that were pumping out hot air into my face like I stood beneath
a space shuttle during a take-off. Oh yeah, those were the days, well no more.
We just built ourselves a cloud based data center there that rivals, and you know what, no doubt surpasses
anything that I have ever been involved with building with my own hands.
The one caveat of course, while I'm saying all of this impressive sounding stuff, you and I actually have
really no way of knowing the details behind what we've created. What I mean is, right, we can't walk
up to an Amazon data center and say, hey don't mind me, I'm just coming in to inspect the kit that my stuff
is running on. No, uh uh, so really while we know Amazon has got awesome facilities, right, we have no
visibility into what kind of tests and maintenance and anything like that that Amazon might or might not
be carrying out. Like just for instance, okay, a bunch of companies I've worked with in the past
have done things like annual power maintenance tests, UPS tests, all of that kind of jazz, yeah.
Making sure that the physical facilities and kit are well oiled and work as they should.
Now don't get me wrong, I'm not saying you should massively sweat over this, we can assume that Amazon
does this kind of stuff, okay, it's just no longer looming on our radars, which if you've ever been involved
in any stuff like that before, you are going to know is a good thing.
One less thing to plan and stress over, yeah. But you know what?
If your company has never bothered with stuff like that before, then anything that you do get like that
from Amazon behind the scenes is a total bonus. Point is though, what kind of testing are Amazon really doing?
I don't know. Anyway, never mind that. Give yourselves a well deserved pat on the back while we review
just exactly what we've built for ourselves.