Okay then, if we hit subnets over here, then jump straight into creating a new one, now, I strongly suggest
that you give it some kind of name, okay, that makes it easy for you to tell if it's going to be public
or private. This one's going to be public and our first public subnet in this VPC, yeah.
Honestly though, this is just going to save you a bunch of head scratching and hunting around and stuff
in the future. Consider it like self documentation sort of. Just trust me okay, you'll be glad that you did.
Make it part of our new VPC and choose an availability zone. Now, okay, don't forget how each availability zone
within a region is like its own isolated data center, so that means let's say one of those snazzy flying
delivery drones that Amazon is working with, yeah, well let's say one of them does like divide by 0 midflight
and it comes crashing down on an AWS data center, taking the entire availability zone out with it, right.
Okay, pretty funny news story, assuming nobody's hurt. But it's no big deal for us, right?
As long as we've deployed our apps in a highly available fashion across multiple availability zones
because the thing to grock here, right, is that an availability zone being taken out, even in style like that,
right, isn't going to impact any AWS services running in other availability zones.
Now, okay, we're getting ahead of ourselves here, we've not covered highly available designs yet.
So 1b is going to be just fine for now. Then the CIDR block, okay.
And I'm sure we know this by now, this is a slice of addresses taken from the pool of addresses that the VPC holds.
In fact, let's swipe this guy on here, yeah, remember this one from earlier.
The VPC has got like this big old pool of addresses and then each subnet that we create as part of the VPC
takes a slice of those addresses for itself. Okay, so our VPC was 10.0.0.0, 10 and 3 zeros, right,
with a /16 subnet mask. So for simplicity, we'll say this subnet's going to be 10.0.1.0/24 and yes we'd like to
create that. And that's a very basic subnet for us, but we're going to want 2 for later on okay.
One public for accessing the internet directly and the other one for private without direct internet access.
So I'm going to do that again, only this time for a private subnet.
Same VPC, same availability zone, and this'll do for the CIDR block.
Okay, right, now then, just to step back for a second and see what we've actually done.
We've created our VPC, yeah, we called it podcast and we assigned it a big old range of addresses.
Then, from within that range of addresses, we sliced ourselves out two subnets, podcast-pub1 and
podcast-priv1. Both in a single availability zone, right? Now then, that's what we've explicitly built, yeah.
But behind the scenes, AWS has thrown in some extra stuff without us knowing, despite the fact, right, that
we're not using a wizard, it's still done it. Mainly what it's added is a router and some routing tables.
And that's what we're going to cover next.