So, there is another way of hooking your corporate network up to your AWS VPCs and it's like, well certainly
in my opinion at least, it's the more enterprise class way to do it, the posh way, you know,
like VPNs are maybe connections for the common man or woman, whereas this, this is for the serious customer.
So it's like more reliable, gives you better and more consistent throughput, lower latency, just an all around
better, more high grade option. Oh, and it's called Direct Connect.
Maybe I should have left that off the slide and given like a drum roll or something.
And it's called Direct Connect. Anyway, the name's like a total gimme.
So it tells us pretty much exactly what it does, which is instead of using the internet as the network
in between our office over here and our VPC, we string a dedicated cable between the two.
Now that's like the mega high level, of course, and we'll look into the detail in uno momento.
But to grasp the big picture, that's pretty much what we need. So, get rid of the internet here,
we don't need that, I mean like it's totally overrated, right? Who needs the internet?
Anyway, we replace it with a dedicated cable and as simple as that, right, we've got ourselves
a nice little connection into AWS, but one without all the baggage that comes with the internet,
so you know, without all the bad guys lurking around every corner trying to nick your data and without
all of the internet traffic jams at rush hour that give us that like totally random performance.
Well, Direct Connect makes pretty much all of that go away. But, and there's always a but, for me at least, okay,
that but lies in the fact that lashing the piece of string or the network circuit between ourselves and AWS,
ah it's not quite as simple as that diagram makes out. I mean it's not mega hard or anything, but you've got
to go through a third party, so you can't just run a cable from one of your own routers directly into AWS.
No. You've got to go through like an AWS Direct Connect access point of sorts or a point of presence or POP,
but all that basically is is a colo data center that's got dedicated network pipes into AWS.
So for example, right, I'm in the UK, yeah, meaning a bunch of people that I work with run their AWS stuff
in the Ireland region, eu-west 1. So, when they need a Direct Connect connection, a Direct Connect connection,
yeah, try saying that 10 times while chewing on a sweet, but anyway, they tend to use the TeleCity data centers
in the London Docklands. The reason being, right, TeleCity, who's got a handful of data centers
in the Docklands area, have got high speed dedicated pipes directly from their own data centers into the
AWS Ireland region. Now, I know maybe all of you don't have infrastructure backgrounds, so I don't want to assume
that you just know what all of that stuff is. So, stick with me, right, while I back up just a second.
A colo data center, right, it's basically a data center facility with space to rent.
So, a company like TeleCity or Equinix or whoever, right, there's tons of them, yeah.
Well they build like a mahoosive data center with top notch facilities, all the bells and whistles, yeah,
and then they rent space out. So maybe they rent out a whole or a room or a cabinet or a caged area, right.
Each of those being like a mini data center, but each one being sold or rented out to different customers.
What we end up with is a big old data center with a bunch of different companies using it.
Anyway, a select group of these colo data centers, and colo is just short for collocation because we have
multiple companies using them, yeah, well a select group of those have got dedicated network connections
from their data centers directly into AWS. Magic. So, I guess it's pretty easy to get your head around this,
right, if you're already in one of those select few colos, in fact actually, if we jump quickly over to our
AWS console here, we go into Direct Connect down here. Look here, we're in Ireland, right?
So there's only two colos to choose from, TeleCity and Eircom, I hope I pronounced that right.
But if we jump over here to US West Oregon, right, oh good option.
So there's Euqinix and SUPERNAP. Now I say it's a good option, right, because as a geek I've kind of drooled
over SUPERNAP facilities in the past, proper like, I don't know, uber data centers.
Very cool to Google and research some time if you're into data centers, SUPERNAP, I'm telling you.
Anyway, you're usually going to find like a couple of colo options, so those AWS Direct Connect
points of presence, yeah, a couple per region is normal. I don't know, maybe they'll be more in the future,
but for now it's usually a couple per region.
Anyway, what I was going to say was, if you're already located in one of those, so you've got your infrastructure
and your kit and your servers and stuff in there, then you kind of sort it or so it would seem.
I mean, surely it can't be that hard to string up some fiber between some of your kit, already in the colo, yeah,
over to one of the routers with access to AWS that the colo provides.
And that's ideal, right? It's basically a fiber cross connect.
So not wickedly hard. Yeah it's going to cost you and you're going to need some networking know how
to be able to do it. Because you're already on site, it's pretty simple.
Cool and all, but what if you're not already in one of those sites?
I don't know, maybe you are in a colo, just not one that's been blessed with connectivity to AWS.
Well, no massive issue actually, it's still totally doable. All you've got to do is work with a Telco provider,
so like Colt or AT&T or Verizon or whoever's in your area and on the list of AWS approved partners,
then what can happen is, these guys can hook you up from your facility or colo into one of those
Direct Connect POPs. So here's you over her in your colo, right, with no access to Direct Connect.
But let's say Colt, right, and substitute those guys with whoever's relevant in your area, these guys
are on the AWS list and have got connectivity into your colo and connectivity into the Direct Connect
point of presence, meaning they can basically act like a middle man, getting you access over here
where you need it. Now obviously there's more to it than that, okay, but conceptually, so long as I did
a half decent job at least, you should pretty grasp the idea of Direct Connect.
Now, I think we did say that it's an alternative way of getting your office access to your VPC,
so instead of using a VPN. Meaning, as a result, all access to resources is done via private IPs again.
So you totally need to make sure that the network addresses of your office and your VPC don't overlap,
because it ain't using the internet, we're on private IPs again here.
I just can't stress this enough, right, when you're getting started with VPCs, treat them like regular
corporate networks, make sure they've got their own documented and separate IP ranges.
Anyway, right, it can also work alongside a VPN, sort of, right.
It's just got to be in an active passive formation. This means that while your Direct Connect link is up
that's going to get used and your VPN, your secure connection over the internet, it's going to be ignored.
But then as soon as your Direct Connect link goes down, your VPN connection kicks in and takes over.
So the two can work together for high availability. But, right, speaking of Direct Connect links going down,
they're like totally not redundant by design, okay. So if you want some sort of high redundancy
within Direct Connect, you're going to need two of them, each with their own dedicated fiber cross connect.
Now then, to do it, right, Direct Connect has got its own icon and its own link from here in the AWS console.
Then, under Connections here, we go to Create Connection. Now we give our connection a name (Typing)
and that'll do for us. Then we get to choose which POP we use, we're in Ireland, so it's either TeleCity
or Eircom and if they're not an option, then we can hit this link here, but we'll go with TeleCity
and we'll have a 10Gbps connection please, I mean, 1Gbps it's like so last year, in fact where's the
100Gbps connections, Amazon? Anyway, we'll create that. Okay so there it is and it's details.
State, requested. Now then, in the real world, right, like as opposed to the alternative reality that I'm
creating this course from, well we'd need to go and get the cross connect in place now.
And that's going to look something like this, okay. We're going to need to speak to our colo or
network provider and we'll give them the authorization email that we'll get from Amazon.
Because yeah, we get an authorization email from them now that we're created that connection request.
And then once we given them that, we go through the motions of physically cabling it all up, yeah.
Once that's done, that state there is going to change from requested and this Create Virtual Interface
spot in here, that's going to light up. Then you're going to create a virtual interface for every VPC
that you want to be reachable over your Direct Connect link. So if you've got four VPCs, you might want to
create four virtual interfaces, assuming you want all four to be reachable over Direct Connect.
But I'm going to let you down again, that's beyond the scope of this course, because as awesome as my
consulting company is, yeah, I'm not yet on the Fortune 100 list.
So I've not bothered to get myself kit in the Direct Connect POP yet and plus, from here on in, right,
it's all networking mumbo jumbo like VLANs and BGP ASNs and router configs and the likes.
But I reckon, right, that's enough to make us cool with Direct Connect, a rich man or woman's VPN,
if you will. I don't know, you want a direct connection into AWS?
You're too important for the internet? Then Direct Connect is the option for you.
But, charges to apply. And on that note, I think we'll go and summarize what we've learned in this module.