Anybody else with a question. Yeah, yep, you. Hello there Nigel.
I'm Mike from the Northeast of England and I want to know, how do I plan against AWS going down?
Whoa, okay. So we're talking about disaster recovery here. Sometimes we call it business continuity.
And you know what? It's probably a mini course on its own. But I suppose, build your apps okay,
and design your infrastructure so that you spread your services across as much of AWS as possible.
I mean, we've talked in the course about things like using multiple availability zones.
So if you've got two front end web servers doing the same thing, stick them both in separate availability zones.
That way if one zone goes down, the other web server is going to survive.
But you know what? You might need to take things even further, so like in all the enterprise environments
I've worked in, we've had two data centers, sometimes more. But they've always been geographically dispersed,
so at least 20 or 25 miles apart. So, in AWS terms, you might want to run services out of like EU-West 1
in Ireland as well as EU-Central in Frankfurt. Or maybe some of your services in an EU region and some
in a US region. And all of this takes planning, obviously. Usually day 1 planning with the app guys
and the infa guys actually talking to each other. But this really is the only way to protect your business
against an entire region going down and this has happened and it will happen again.
So if you're running mission critical stuff and you take your business seriously, like who doesn't?
Then spread your risk as widely as possible. Don't stick all of your eggs into like US-East and then feel a grief
when US-East goes belly up, right. And to mitigate against the whole of AWS going away, I suppose it's feasible
to spread your risk over multiple cloud providers, so maybe AWS and Google Cloud platform or AWS
and Microsoft Azure. Though I'd say, at least at the time of recording, that's like uber bleeding edge stuff,
but I imagine it's going to get more and more common and easier to do in the future.
So keep your eye out for things like that. Whatever you're doing though, yeah, make sure your CIDR blocks
don't overlap with your on-prem corporate networks, yeah.