Okay, so NACLs, yeah, that's what I'm going to be calling them from now on because you know what?
I'm too lazy to say Network access control lists or even Network ACLs or Network A-C-Ls or whatever, right.
Plus, I kind of like the sound of NACLs. Anyway, NACLs are to subnets what security groups are to instances,
firewalls of sorts, yeah. So very similar to security groups, but totally different as well.
So remember back to our picture from earlier, how we've got traffic coming in and it's been expected by
security groups with their inbound and outbound rules and only allowing explicit allow rules, but anything not
explicitly allowed is implicitly denied and how they maintain state.
Well first up, NACLs apply up here at the subnet level and they've got separate rule sets for inbound
and outbound traffic. But, these guys let us explicitly deny traffic as well as explicitly allowing it.
And they're stateless, meaning they don't care if a packet is a legit reply to something already allowed,
if there's no rule specifically allowing it, then it ain't getting passed.
So the two things I reckon that are of note here are the things that make them different to security groups,
sure okay, they operate at the subnet level instead of the instance, but it's these abilities to create
deny rules and the stateless behavior that you really want to note.
And you know what? Amazon might change this in the future. But personally, I think it's a pretty good approach,
you know, it's good to have similar but slightly different technologies at different layers in the stack.
These guys, in my opinion, really complement each other. The combination of the two being a pretty solid mix.
Anyway, they look like this, kind of similar to security groups, yeah, but a couple of big old differences,
oh, well, first off up here it's reminding us, yeah that they're stateless, but it's this rule number column here
where I want you to notice because when traffic hits a NACL rules start getting checked in order, so in
numeric order. That means rule #100 here gets checked first, and I don't know, let's say that the traffic
we're inspecting is encrypted web traffic, well rule 100 here doesn't match, so the next rule gets checked,
rule #200, that's TCP 443, you know what? Looks like encrypted web traffic to me.
So that's a match. And processing of the rules stops. No need to check anymore, we've hit a match,
so we can make a decision. Well this rule here says allow here at the end, so we let the traffic on through.
And that is totally different to security groups where all rules always get processed.
But let's do another example, let's say the traffic coming in and being expected was aimed at the Docker remote API
on TCP 2375, okay, we check rule 100, no match, 200, no match, 300, still no match, and then this funny looking
fellow down here with the asterisk. Well that says all traffic, all protocols, on all ports, from anywhere.
Well that sure as hell matches and it says deny, so the packet would get dropped.
The asterisk rule being the default catchall rule for when none of the other rules apply or match
I suppose should say. You know what? You might hear it referred to as the default deny all rule.
And NACLs are stateless, so they couldn't care less, right, whether a packet is part of a legit conversation.
If there's no rule specifically allowing the traffic, then big red down here is going to grab it and toss it
over the wall.
Now this behavior of rules being processed in strict numeric order and then as soon as a match is hit we say
we're good, we don't need to bother checking anymore rules, well let me tell you, knowing something like that
is pure gold when you're troubleshooting network problems and you've got like a shed load of NACL and
security group rules to wade through. Seriously, pure gold. Ah, that reminds me of something else,
remember we said, in fact we showed it actually, that multiple security groups can be associated
with a single instance. Well not so with NACLs, right? Each subnet can only have a single NACL attached to it,
though a single NACL can be attached to multiple subnets. And you know what?
If you've ever administered routers on network firewalls in the past, or even written good old basic programs
where ever line had to be numbered and the number automated, well you'll already know the power of sticking
to a numbering style like this where we go up in either 10s or 100s.
It just means if you need to stick a rule in between, let's say 200 and 300, well we can just name it 250
and it'll automatically get inserted in between the two, whereas if we'd named them 2 and 3, well,
good luck with that, yeah, because while we can delete rules in a NACL we can't modify them in place.
Okay, well rounding out our NACL theory, we can have 200 NACLs per VPC, but only 20 rules per NACL
and you know what? If you're new to this, 20 rules might seem like a lot, but many seasoned networking pros
out there will tell, it ain't. Though, taking a ridiculously positive outlook on things, keeping this number
of rules in the NACL small is really quite a good thing. For one it's going to make troubleshooting
a relative walk in the park compared to something with hundreds of rules.
But it's also going to help performance because processing hundreds of rules, that takes time.
So Amazon is forcing us to keep things simple and I'm a fan of that, though I'm often a realist too,
and I totally get that it can be limiting. But it is what it is.
Now that's the theory done, let's go and play with them in the real world.