So over to EC2,
in fact, you know what, let's stick these up here. Should save us a bit of time I think (Typing).
Okay, let's go launch an instance. You know what? Let's go with the AWS Linux AMI this time or A-M-I,
whatever you want to call it. T2 micro will do for us. And here we go.
We'll have our podcast VPC thanks and obviously we want our public subnet and then see here, auto-assign
public IP, we can either go with the subnet's default setting, which is the bit in parens, obviously
that's enabled since we just set that, or we can manually override the setting.
Well the subnet's default of enable is fine with us, but just remember this is where we can override it if we need to.
Okay, next. Next. Yep, we'll name ours (Typing). That'll do. And I think the security group config
is going to work for us, right, we're just going to try SSH and let's launch.
Right, a key pair and off it goes (Loading). Now while this spins itself up, let's go see it's public IP.
There it is, 52.18.112.214. A full on, bona fide, publically routable IP address.
Well let's grab a copy of it, in fact, no, let's go with the public DNS name.
We'll open up a command prompt and let's see if we can ping it. Bingo.
Well, okay it's not accepting pings, but we can see that we can resolve the DNS name to its public IP address.
Okay, well let's configure PuTTY here, so we'll go in there, we'll tell it to use our podcast keys,
we downloaded those and converted them to the PPK format earlier in the course.
Let's make the font a decent size and we'll connect (Loading). Oh, not exactly what we wanted.
I'll tell you what, let me give it another go, just in case it's still firing up.
No, not looking good. Okay, IP address 112.241, yeah that's right.
Let's check the security group, yep, SSH allowed. Let's go look at the NACL, I know we've not covered this yet,
but needs must (Loading). Inbound, yes to all. I wonder if we've got a route to the internet, yep.
Oh, look, no subnet associations. Did we forget to associate this when we created it?
I guess we did. Okay, let's associate it with our public subnet.
Should we try this again (Loading)? Ah, that's miles better. Whooo wee, we went with the AWS AMI, right?
Yeah, back to business now. Okay, so IP addresses. Oh, hang on a second.
Where's the public IP? That's just the loopback in the private addresses there.
Are we missing something? No, same again here, just the loopback and the private address.
So Linux knows nothing about the public IP address. But we know it works, right?
I mean we've just SSH'ed into the thing using its public IP. So what's going on?
Does it have a public IP or doesn't it? Well, we're witnessing a little bit of AWS magic here,
but not hidden dark magic. So not like the secret source of the internet gateway we talked about earlier,
although this is actually internet gateway magic, it's just not secret this time.
So what is going on here? Our Linux instance, and it could just as easily be a Windows instance, right?
But it knows nothing about any public IP address, we just saw that.
All it knows about is its private IP. Then on the internet gateway we've got a bit of NAT magic going on,
network address translation. So basically, the internet gateway is holding a mapping of private IPs
to public IPs. So every time our instance here sends a packet to the internet, the internet gateway, yeah,
it sends the packet out to the internet, but stamped with the public IP of the instance.
Then any replies that come back, well they get converted back to the instance's private IP before they get
delivered back onto the VPC. Dead simple, but dead effective too.
The internet gateway just takes care of making sure that any internet bound requests in or out get mapped
to the appropriate public IP for that instance. So just in case you weren't already impressed at the
horizontal scalableness and super nitroglycerin enhanced performance of the internet gateway, well guess what?
It performs a bunch of NAT magic too. I don't know, next it'll be making you coffee.
But the sweet thing, remember, we created it with like a couple of mouse clicks, unbelievable.
But there we go, a public subnet in all of its wonder and glory.
Internet gateways, route table entries, and public IP addresses.
The only problem we're left with now, when we reboot the instance it's going to lose that public IP
and get a totally new one. What? You heard that right. Totally non-persistent.
Here today, gone tomorrow. No good for anything permanent. What?
Well, no big deal, it's easily fixable.