Now then, in order to get this right, I think we could do with a quick refresher to remind us a bit
of how we've got our networks configured. So we've got our podcast VPC and in there we've got that Linux instance
in a public subnet, you know, the one that's trying to ping another Linux instance over in a private subnet
in the blog VPC. And we've got things configured so that each VPC has got two custom route tables,
one's for public subnets and the other is for private. So, because we want this public instance,
if I can call it that, to talk to this private instance over here, we're going to need to update the public
routing table on this side and the private routing table on that side.
What this'll do is make sure that instances in the public subnet here know about the new route to the private
subnet over here and a corresponding route back. Cool.
And just in case we forget, I've got a mini version that I'm going to park up here, I'm going to keep my
fingers crossed that it doesn't get in the way. So from Chrome here, so our podcast VPC, we want to hit Route Tables
and according to our little picture up here we want the public one, so this one.
Then hit Routes and add a new one. Now we want to be telling it about the blog VPC, again, a little pic
at the top here tells us that that's 172.16.0.0/16. And well, as if by magic, there's our pcx object.
Pcx standing for peering connection. Save that and why not, let's just make sure it's associated
with our public subnets, which yes it is. So that's one side done.
Our podcast public subnets now know how to get to our blog VPC. So if we jump to the blog side now
and same again, Route Tables, all nicely name again, we want this one, blog route table local, Routes,
and add a new one. This time our little picture is telling us we want 10.0.0.0/16 and our peer connection
object again. Now interesting, okay, if we want to we can put in like a smaller range of IPs,
we could put in just one of the subnets just back in our podcast VPC or we could even put a single IP address
from that range. So there is flexibility. Anyway, here comes the moment of truth, and this better work,
so let's, we'll move this over here a bit, bring our ping machine back.
Nope still not pinging. Then if we hit Save, yes. There we go.
Two instances in separate VPCs belonging to separate AWS accounts, not that that matters, but it sounds
a bit better, having a polite conversation over private IPs. Marvelous.
Let's go and wrap the module up.