Okay, so we've got our two web servers up and working. And we've configured our elastic load balancer
to know all about them. So, now all that's done, we need to stop accessing our web service directly
and start accessing them through the load balancer. Well, to do that, we're going to need either the IP address
or the DNS name of the load balancer, which brings us to our first major point.
Amazon doesn't expose the load balance's IP addresses, just its DNS name, and there's sound reasoning
for that. You see, the elastic part of elastic load balancer means it's flexible, so the load balancer
grows and shrinks based on how much traffic it's handling, only we really need to think of it as a
load balancing service and it's therefore the service that grows and shrinks.
So, okay, behind the scenes, right, it's something like this. When we start out, our load balancer
comes prepackaged as some standard size. And then let's say over time the amount of load that it's handling
increases. Well, when that happens, the actual load balancer behind the scenes, so the nuts and bolts, yeah,
well that might actually get swapped out for a bigger instance and that kind of switch makes the IP address
or addresses behind the load balancer's DNS name, it makes them change.
So the net effect, right, over time, the IP addresses servicing our load balancers are going to be changing.
But the corollary, it's DNS name, doesn't, Amazon makes sure of that.
But it can also happen that it scales out as well, so we end up with multiple IPs behind that DNS name.
It really doesn't matter though, the point being, as the elastic load balancer flexes, so grows and shrinks
based on demand and requirements, the IP addresses behind it are going to change, fluid yeah.
Not to be trusted. Moral of the story, just always use the DNS name.
And of course, while that's no bad thing, it does have a few knock on effects that you're going to want to consider.
One of those, for example, being that you can't white list the load balancer's IP addresses because they change.
So for its DNS name that we can see here, yeah, we can just whack that into a browser session, that means
our web traffic is going to go to the load balancer, which in turn is going to balance it over our two
backend web servers. So 1b this time and if we hit refresh, 1a.
Refresh again and we how it's flipping between the two. Well I don't want this to be an anticlimax or anything,
but that there is our elastic load balancer in all its glory or all its glory is a bit harsh,
because that is a fairly mundane task we're asking it to do. Remember we said earlier, it can do things like
accept HTTPS traffic and then pass that on internally as plain HTTP, effectively offloading our
SSL connections, though I shouldn't really say SSL anymore, TLS, yeah.
And you know what else? This is common as well, so the DNS name that it's been given by Amazon is a bit ugly, yeah.
Well, if we jump over to GoDaddy over here or wherever your DNS servers are, yeah, well I've got this unused
domain name here called tech-force-one.com, it's just from back when we were deciding on a name for the podcast
that I co-host. I think we were deciding between In Tech We Trust and Tech Force One.
Well at the time I just registered both domain names in case. Anyway, tech-force-one is unused,
so if I add a record here, a CNAME, so an alias, and then say www.tech-force-one.com, we're going to point that
to that heaviest long name that Amazon gave our elastic load balancer here, yep redirect that monstrosity,
and a time to live of 1 hour is fine. So, save that, and what it's going to do is, right, it's going to
let us use the friendly tech-force-one.com domain name to access our load balancers, which in turn
gives us access to our web servers. And this is guaranteed to work, yeah, because that hideous long DNS name
that our load balancer got given, Amazon guaranteed that that is not going to change.
So, if we go to that browser session again, and change it to www.tech-force-one.com, bingo.
And cycling through then, yeah, we flip-flop between both just as we'd expect.
Now then, I just want to point out one last thing before we go and do a recap of what we've learned.
There's always going to be a lag when the elastic load balancer decides it needs to scale.
So between the time that traffic increases, yeah, and the time that the load balancer responds by scaling
to meet that increased demand and there definitely are corner cases or niche requirements, yeah,
where this can be a challenge. So what I'd say is expect a minimum, right, of probably about 90 seconds
before you see any scaling really start to happen. But that's just a minimum, it can be a bit more,
and part of the reason for this, right, is that there's a 60 second time to live, or TTL, placed on the
load balancer's DNS record, not the one we just created in GoDaddy, the one that Amazon maintains mapping
that hideous long name to any IP addresses behind it. But what this means, right, is there's going to be 60 seconds
before any changes to the IPs of the backend load balancing nuts and bolts services, yeah, actually get
reflected in the real world. Remember, yeah, when scaling that load balancer, the newly scaled service
has brand new IPs behind the DNS record and it's therefore going to be 60 seconds before those new IPs
start getting used. And remember, there's also the health checks that we talked about before, so both are
potential delays, right, to the overall time it takes your app to respond positively to changes in traffic patterns.
Anyway, it's still cracking stuff and if it doesn't totally meet your needs, go and pair it up with a third party
load balancer too. Enough of that though, let's go quickly remind ourselves of the main things that we learned.