So I'm guessing right, for most production apps and the likes
you're going to want persistent public IPs, at least for some of your internet facing systems.
Maybe you need some of your clients to internally white list some public IPs so that when you come talking to them
they can trust you. Well public IPs, like we've just been working with, are definitely not the answer to that.
They don't belong to you and they change every time an instance reboots.
So what we really want are what Amazon calls elastic IPs. Now these puppies are the same as public IPs
in that obviously they're kosher publically routable addresses and we've still no control over which particular
addresses we get, but they are ours to keep. And bouncing an instance isn't going to cause it's elastic IP address
to change. In fact, the only time that an elastic IP gets released back to Amazon is if we explicitly say so.
So to get one, we jump over here to elastic IPs
and what the heck, I haven't got any. Well I'll tell you why in just a sec, but we just go Allocate New Address
and there we go. So this is here is why I've not got any right now.
I've obviously had them in the past, but once I'm done with them and I've trashed the instances they map to
I give them back. Because while they're in use you don't get charged, although actually, I think you do
if you've got maybe more than one per instance or something like that, but I'd check the latest pricing info.
But once they're not in use there is a small charge to pay. Anyway, we want one so we'll say yes thanks
and it's just thinking and there it is. Now all we need to do is go associate it with an instance
or an elastic network interface. For simplicity sake, okay, we're going to attach it to the instance
that we just fired up a second ago. But normally, not normally, but certainly the more powerful option
is to associate it with an elastic network interface and all that is is well, a network card, but one that
we can associate and re-associate with pretty much any instance we want.
So if we were to associate an elastic IP with an ENI, that's an elastic network interface, we can attach
and detach that interface from different instances easy as pie, though stating the obvious I hope,
it can only be attached to one instance at a time. It's pretty powerful, but we're not going to get
sidetracked right now. So yes and there we go. It we jump back over to EC2, see I told you that shortcut
would save us some time, and we select our instance, well see here how the public IP and the elastic IP
are both populated with the same address. So, for reliable, persistent, public IP addresses we need elastic IPs.
These get assigned to our VPC and then we can assign them to instances or elastic network interfaces.
And again, as far as our instances are concerned, they work the same as public IPs, meaning Linux or Windows
or whatever knows nothing about them. It's all magically and invisibly mapped on the internet gateway.
So let's say, okay, generally speaking, elastic IPs are where it's at for publically routable IPs.
Definitely what you want if you need something persistent and reliable.
I've got a little note here as well saying, at the time of recording at least, there is a limit of five per VPC.
And you know what? I reckon that's all I've got to say on public subnets.
Next up, we'll have a quick look at how we configure private subnets for accessing the internet.