So we get to NACLs from the VPC dashboard down here next to Security Groups.
And as we can see, against this account that I'm using right now, we'll we've currently got three.
So that's one for each of the three VPCs that I've got. And see how all of them are shown as default?
Well that's because every VPC when it gets created automatically gets given a default NACL and then it's this
that gets applied to any new subnets that we create. Now there's nothing really special about a default NACL,
so we can edit it if we want to or if we'd prefer we can just associate a different NACL with each of our subnets.
So if we look at the one associated with our two subnets here, see how it's got an inbound rule here
that allows all traffic? Remember, that default deny all rule here gets processed last.
So rule 100 here, allow all traffic types on all protocols on all ports from anywhere and everywhere,
that's going to match everything and it's going to be processed before big red down here and as it's an allow rule
all inbound traffic is good to go. And the same goes over here for the outbound interface.
Rule 100, again, allowing anything and everything. So for the time being, right, from a security perspective,
this NACL is about as much use as a solar powered fog light or an ejector seat in a helicopter, yeah,
not much use at all. But we're absolutely able to edit it and add new rules and the likes.
You know what? Instead of that, let's go and create a new one from scratch.
Let's call it podcast-pub-NACL and stick it on our podcast VPC. Okay it's having to think.
And there it is, not associated with any subnets though, and not a default NACL.
But before we do associate it with a subnet, let's add some inbound rules.
And as it's good practice, we'll start with rule 100. Now we'll make this one for SSH traffic.
Now picking it from this drop down list or drop up list, all this does is it populates the protocol
and the port sections for us and then we can decide if it's an allow rule or a deny rule.
Now generally speaking, okay, 99.9 something % of rules are going to be allow rules.
Deny rules, well they just make life a misery when things go wrong.
Seriously, for such a simple and seemingly innocent thing, deny rules have like this evil power that'll make
your hair go gray and probably start falling out. You might not think so, they look like so innocent,
but it's so flipping true. Try and avoid them. Now in saying that, right, I'm not saying you should never
create them, but do have a long hard think about it before you do and if you can try and work things out
so that the default deny all rule is enough. Anyway, we'll add a couple more allows, one for HTTP (Typing)
and one for HTTPS, oh go on, and one more as a custom rule (Typing), 2375 for talking to the Docker remote API.
And for this one, yeah we'll say only hosts in our 10.0.2 network.
Oh, don't forget to give it a number. And then for all of these ones up here, we'll say from any source (Typing).
Looks good to me (Loading). Now for outbound rules. Right, just the default denial rule, so currently
operating under like a level 10 lockdown, nothing is getting out.
Well that's no fun (Typing). So we'll say, all traffic, it already says all protocols and ports,
and we'll say that this traffic can go anywhere (Typing). Okay, hmm.
This is fairly standard practice for outbound NACLs, but it's not massively secure though.
So you might not want to do this in production, like leave it wide open like this.
But for our lab demo here, ah, I'm not going to lose any sleep. So basically, right, we don't mind
what traffic gets out, but coming in, yeah we're a bit more particular, only allowing SSH, HTTP, HTTPS,
and traffic heading for the Docker remote API endpoint. Good. But it's not attached to any subnets yet.
So if we edit this and we'll associate it with our public subnet (Loading).
Now doing that, associating it with our public subnet, automatically kicks off any of the NACL that was already
associated with that subnet and that was the VPC's default NACL.
Remember, we can only stick one NACL on any subnet. Now, while it's live and active on our public subnet,
we can still go in and edit it's rules and seeing as how this is attached to our public subnet,
I don't really want 2375 open, so I'll just delete it, and this one down here that it thought I was going to create,
and I'll give it a save. And there it is, it's gone. Now if we jump up to our instances up here,
come down and grab that public IP again (Typing), and let's fire off a connection to it (Typing).
Log in as ec2-user and we're in.
Now blasting through it, right. The podcast public route table here, it's got a route to the internet,
and that's obviously very important. Without it, no traffic can get in or out, internet traffic that is.
And we can see, it's associated with the public subnet that we've got our instance in.
Then network ACLs here, ah, I just called it a Network ACL, not a NACL, anyway it's got an inbound rule
allowing SSH and it's got an outbound rule allowing all traffic out.
We need that, otherwise responses can't get back to us. And for security groups, ah, we get a better view
from the instance itself. Yeah, see down here, right, a couple of security groups, but importantly
a rule, again allowing SSH traffic. And that's like how it all fits together.
Let's go and recap what we've learned in the module now.