Routing, routing, routing.
The first thing to note is exactly where the route is drawn on the diagram.
It's at the VPC level, so one per VPC. And if we add a couple of lines to it, yeah, we can see how it routes
traffic between our two subnets. That's the job of the router, right, to let instances or containers on one subnet
talk with other subnets, conceptually it's mega simple. Then, in each subnet we have a routing table.
These tell us how to get traffic from one subnet to another. I think maybe we need an analogy here.
I suppose we could say that the routing tables are a bit like directions, maybe road signs or something, yeah,
and the routers themselves are the roads. Now don't stress if that's not making sense right now.
It totally will as we progress, especially as we start looking at how to get out onto the internet.
For now though, route tables are like directions, where do I want to go?
Another subnet? Okay, hit this router. I want to go to the internet, okay, hit another router.
The routers themselves being like roads. Anyway the next thing to point out is that our AWS router
is like 100% totally hip software defined goodness. I can guarantee they're not giving you some Juniper
or Cisco router in there, no way. This is bona fide software defined networking.
We don't need to worry about the state of the router, so is it up, it is down?
How are the power supply units? What's the temperature? All of that kind of stuff, no concern of ours.
We don't need to think about how to configure it for high availability, we don't need to manage port counts,
nothing like that. We just need to care about the rules that tell it where to send packets, that's the
route table entries, the directions, yeah. I mean, look here in the UI, there ain't no option for routers
or router configs, just this route tables option here. But before we look at route tables, okay, this business
of not being able to log on to the router and the likes is a two-edged sword.
On the one hand, yeah, it makes our lives a lot simpler, no networking voodoo to stress about, but on
the other hand we've got a lot less control. Um, you know what? I can see how this kind of stuff is a bit
of a worry for some people. I mean, for instance, we can't get stats directly from the router, what the heck?
I mean we can't even ping the thing, right. So it's good and it's not so good at the same time.
Now, if we go over to subnets here and our public subnet and hit the Route Table tab, right, we can see
our route table's ID, rtb-22b whatever, yeah, I mean that is crying out for a friendly name.
But down here, we can see the route table entries or in this case entry in a singular, right now our route table
has only got a single lonely entry and that 10.0.0.0/16 address, come on, that should look familiar by now,
it's the network we assigned to our VPC. Now, this combo here of the VPC CIDR block plus the target called local,
this is the route or the direction if we keep with our analogy, that traffic needs to take if it wants to talk
to another device within our VPC. Should be pretty easy to remember since the target says local.
And you know what? Every route table gets this entry and I don't think we can even delete it, so from a
routing perspective, every device that we spin up in any subnet has got access to directions telling it
how to get to every other device in our VPC. And I stress, okay, this is from a routing perspective
because, yeah, we can use things like network access control lists or security groups to lock things down
and disallow traffic and the likes, but as far as network routing goes, this route table entry here
means we're all family within our VPC.