So staying inside of our AWS console for the time being,
what have we got? Well there we go. We can see we've got our new VPC, podcast, yeah.
We've got a quick snapshot of what our VPC consists of and most of this stuff, at least at the time or recording,
right, is shown to us as hideous AWS resource name mumbo jumbo, but we can see our VPC has an ID.
We can see the networks that we've assigned to it and notice, right, that of the three VPCs that I've currently got,
they've all got different network addresses and this'll be really important later on when we try and
connect them to each other. We've got DHCP stuff, routing stuff, access control lists, tenancy,
the default, right, being we just want to share physical servers on the back end with everyone else,
that's what default means. The other option, remember, being for those of us with money to burn who want their own
dedicated physical servers on the back end and you know what though?
Maybe you've got some kosher requirements for that kind of thing, but we're on the cheap on this course, right?
We're happy to share our back end with anyone and everyone. Ah, and default okay, the default VPC,
you can only have one per region, right? This is something that AWS creates automatically for you in each region,
so you'll have one default VPC automatically created for you in each region.
And all it is, right is the VPC that any instances and the likes get deployed into unless we specifically choose
to drop them into a different VPC. Now then okay, subnets here.
And I've got a handful or so, okay, but we see straight away the value of naming them.
I mean we can instantly pick out our private and public subnets that we just created, right, but who the heck
knows what those ones that I've not bothered to label are for. Moral of the story, remember label your stuff.
Now then, time to reveal the mystery of this public subnet business.
So, if we take a look at the route table down here associated with our public subnet, right, this rule here,
0.0.0.0/0, well this is like the default route for the subnet, so the catchall route that gets used
when there's no better matches. And this device here that that traffic gets sent to, starting with igw,
is an internet gateway, a router that routes traffic to the internet.
And you know what? If we compare it to our private subnet up here, yeah, see how that doesn't send traffic
to an igw or to an internet gateway? Well, that there, at least at the time or recording, is the major difference
between public and private subnets. A public subnet has got a route to the internet via an internet gateway
and a private subnet doesn't. This other route, this one here, oop, well both subnets have got this.
And what it does is it lets traffic flow locally between subnets without our VPC.
Okay, cool and all, but it doesn't throw any light onto the mystery of why our public subnet here,
why it's got a private network that's not even routable on the internet.
Well, let's unravel this mystery. You know what right? We're going to be coming back to all of this
in more detail later, but this old boy here, okay, auto-assign public IP, this is where the magic happens
or actually this is where we turn the magic on because the magic actually happens on the internet gateway.
But this setting, right, it's a subnet wide setting, okay, and if we enable it, so we go up here and then we hit
this modify auto-assign public IP option, what this is going to do is anytime we launch an instance
into this subnet, it's going to get a public IP. So a proper, bonafide publically routable address,
none of this RFC 1918 internal only, not publically routable stuff, no every instance is then going to get
its very own public IP address, only the way it works, right, and let's say this first, but the way it works
is that each instance still only gets a private IP address from the RFC 1918 CIDR block range down here.
But then the internet gateway performs some NATting magic where it maps a public IP address to a private
IP address. You get what I'm saying or at least I hope you do, right?
Every instance will then a public IP address associated with its private IP address on the internet gateway.
So the internet gateway holds a mapping, making it look and feel like the instances have their own public IPs.
Anyway, we're going to cover this stuff properly later in the course and I'll draw pictures and diagrams
and all of that kind of jazz, okay. For now, right, we know that public subnets 1) have a route to an
internet gateway, meaning they can get out to the internet and if we want instances in that subnet to be
directly addressable on the internet with public IPs, we can do that too, thanks to a bit of NAT magic
done by the VPC's internet gateway. Wowzers.