Okay, what did we learn in this module?
Well two things basically, first up VPNs.
A cost effective and convenient way to lash our existing sites and networks up to our AWS VPC.
But, using the internet to string the two together. Though that's like not the end of the world, right,
these are proper site to site IPsec VPNs, so they're robust, reliable, and secure.
But seeing as how they use the internet in the middle, they also object to the kind of latency and
throughput challenges that we all love about the internet. But you know what?
Don't let that put you off totally. They really can be the bizzo.
We also pointed out, right, that once these VPN connections are up and working, we can then connect
to our instances in AWS from our office networks using private IPs.
And this is cracking, right? It makes them look and feel like regular old services that are on our
corporate network rather than distant cloud services that we need to access over the internet.
It's really a good thing. Then, we looked at Direct Connect, kind of like the VPN's big brother.
These, right, allow us to run dedicated fiber connections directly from our infrastructure into AWS
or actually via an approved partner. But the point being, we're on dedicated fiber links now
and we're not shifting traffic over the internet. As a result, right, these are going to give us much more
reliable and consistent network performance and most importantly, at least in most cloud computing use cases,
higher throughput. Now of the two big networking measurements, right, latency and throughput,
I'd say in the majority of cases, throughput is the killer for cloud computing.
Because I figure, right, in most cases, high latency is a given, yeah.
I mean even using Direct Connect, you're not going to get the kind of low latencies that you can get
if everything's in your own data center. So on your own layer 2 network or your own fiber channel SAN
or whatever, you're not going to get those kind of latencies. It really is throughput that's the killer.
I mean, you want to maybe backing up and restoring to S3 or Glacier or something or doing data analytics
on large data stores that you've got in AWS. Latency is usually not even part of the conversation.
It's all about how much data you can shift back and forth between yourself and AWS.
Well, if that's the case, Direct Connect can be a proper golden ticket to the cloud for you.
Anyway, we said we can have both, so Direct Connect and VPNs, but if we do that, the Direct Connect links
are going to be the preferred ones as long as they're up and then if and when they're down, the VPN
connection kicks in and saves the day. Well, all good stuff, right?
Next up, well a change of gears actually. We're going to wrap the course up with a bit of a quick Q and A with me,
me asking the questions and me giving the answers, how's about that for a rigged set up, yeah?
A bit like a dictatorship. I'll answer any question, so long as I get to see it first and allow only the easy ones.
In fact, what am I talking about? I even wrote the questions and I get to edit the video, talk about
an easy ride. Anyway, see you there in the next module.