Now every VPC gets an implied router, it's just there.
It can neither be created nor can it be destroyed, a bit like NRG app, that's how fundamental this AWS stuff is,
not quite, but anyway. It's just there and it just works. I don't really like that personally.
I like to know the detail, but Amazon aren't giving a lot away about this stuff.
Also, every subnet needs a route table.
So if we've got three subnets here, they all need a subnet. They all need a subnet, I mean they all need
a route table. But each subnet can only have one route table. So we can't say, hey subnet 1 over here,
he or she can have 3 route tables, uh-uh, our survey says uh-uh, but a single route table on the other hand,
totally possible for that to be associated with multiple subnets.
Now then, let's jump back to our AWS console.
Okay, when a VPC gets created it automatically gets a main route table.
See how some of these are tagged as main route tables? Well, when it comes to route tables, it's dead easy
to flip back and forth between being a main route table and being a non-main route table.
We just right click the one that's not the main, this one, and we say set as main table.
Now I'm not going to do that because this one's actually an alive VPC where I'm doing some testing on
Docker Trusted Registry, but if I did click set as main table, then this one up here, which is currently
the main table for that VPC, it's going to get demoted to being a non-main table.
You know, not that it's actually a demotion, but you get, right how a VPC can only have one main table.
They should have probably called it the default route table or something, I don't know.
But what does a main table mean? Well it just means that anytime a new subnet gets created it automatically
gets linked to the VPC's main route table. So if we pick our podcast one again, and I'm going to name it actually
while we're here (Typing), okay, then if I hit Subnet Associations down here, see how it's got two associations?
Our public and our private subnets. But look, see how they're not explicit associations?
That means we didn't manually create them. They just got associated by default because this is the VPC's
main route table, yeah. Well I'm not a fan of that, okay. Mainly because see up here the 0 subnets,
this could be misleading. I mean, not massively so, right, because we can see here it says explicitly
associated subnets, so there are 0 explicitly associated subnets.
But I don't know, it's entirely possible that someone comes along and thinks, ah, this route table is not
associated with any subnets, so let me go and mess with it. Not ideal, no.
So let's edit here, select our public and private, save that. Look that's tons better, well in my opinion it is.
Anyway, every subnet needs a route table and every new subnet gets the VPC's main route table.
And that's okay and we are free to modify and tweak the main route table.
There's nothing super special about it that stops us doing that and you know what?
You might choose to do that, but again, I'm not a fan. I prefer to leave the main table as it is
and then to create a new one and put my funky new custom rules in the new one.
This way, right, anything funky that I do, it doesn't get automatically applied to new subnets and that's
probably a good idea. So I'd create a new one, give it a meaningful name obviously, 10 lashes for anybody
not naming their stuff, put it in the podcast VPC, and create (Loading).
And if we find it now, yeah, see how it's got a default local route, in fact, yeah, see how you can't even
delete that route? It's etched in stone. Then if we go and associate it with a subnet (Loading),
again, we'll pick our two, save them, lovely. So, a new route table in our VPC, not the main table,
meaning any changes we make to it don't get automatically associated with any new subnets that we create,
but it is associated with our two subnets. That's the way I like to rock and roll.
I don't know, okay, you might go about it differently, but in my head, right, this keeps things nice and clean.
Now then, we've only touched the tip of the iceberg when it comes to routing.
But we'll take what we've learned so far, right, and we'll build on that in the next module when we look at
how to get out to the internet and the likes. But first up, let's quickly recap the main points that we've learned
in this module.