Now I reckon we have a couple more things that need explaining
before we're ready to dig a bit deeper. First up, right, we can easily change a subnet that we've labeled
as private to public and public to private. Did that sound right?
Okay, so the only real difference between a public and a private subnet is what we just said, right?
A public subnet has got a route to an internet gateway. So if we change our private subnet routing table
so that it sends all of its unknown traffic to an internet gateway, well that private subnet for all intents
and purposes, becomes a public subnet. What I'm saying is, there's like no special hidden setting or anything
that says once we've created something as a public subnet though shalt always be a public subnet or a
private subnet thou shalt always be a private subnet, no. It really is just whether or not it's logically
hooked up to the VPC's internet gateway and all that takes is the creation of a route within the subnet.
I mean our private subby here, okay, oh that's not good, oh right, maybe my session timed out or something,
at least that's what I hope. Right, where were we? Oh yeah and we look good, okay.
Anyway we can see, okay, that it's possible for our private subnet here to auto-assign public, yes public,
IPs to its instances, no sweat. It's totally doable. But even if we configure it to do that it's not really
a public subnet. To be a public subnet, like we've said, I'm rattling on about this too much now, I get that okay,
but it's got to have a route to the VPCs internet gateway. So keep that in mind, right.
Just because the subnet started out its life as a private subnet, we can tweak its settings and make it public
and vice versa of course. Anyway, another thing we need to know.
We can see that our subnets have got access control lists too. Now as things stand, okay, all traffic is allowed,
so about as much use as a chocolate fire-guard. But these ACLs are totally editable, meaning we can tweak them
to lock things down and obviously we will as we crack on with the course, but the point is, as we can see here,
we've got the ability to create inbound and outbound, allow and deny rules and that is pretty darn flexible.
Now I suppose, right, we should mention the whole point of VPCs, yeah, that is to run applications.
Well, in AWS we run apps in either containers or EC2 instances, and just to keep the learning curve of this course
as unsteep as possible, I'm pretty sure unsteep isn't really a word, but to keep the learning curve of the courses
properly, I'm having a brain freeze here, maybe keep it as shallows as possible, anyway to keep things simple,
yeah, we're just going to stick with EC2 instances, AWS virtual machines if you will.
So let's go and fire one up (Loading).
Now I'm going to go with Ubuntu and free tier is good. Now importantly actually, we're going to need to configure
our instance details, otherwise AWS is just going to launch it into our account default VPC.
But we don't want that, we actually want to stick it in the VPC that we just created.
So here we can choose our podcast VPC and in a second we're going to see if we can access it from the internet,
so we'll stick it in the public subnet. See again, right, the importance of naming our stuff.
Next, we get the chance to override the subnet setting of whether or not the instance gets assigned a public IP,
but see how our subnet setting is already enabled? Well seeing as how that's the case, we'll just stick
with the default, and you know what? That's enough for now.
We don't need to bother about anything on this screen for now, well, I mean that big old scary warning
up there is just telling us that the security group config is wide open.
Store that one for later, right, we'll tackle it in due course. Let's spin her up.
Oh yeah, we need to associate the instance with a key pair. It doesn't really matter which set as long as
you're in possession of them. Podcast keys will do for me. Now we can launch.