In this lesson we'll configure things so that instances in our private subnet can get access to the internet.
But we're going to do it in a way that's totally different to how we just did it with our public subnet,
the reason, right, we don't want our private subnet to have full on access to the internet.
So what we're going to build here is going to be a bit more restricted, you know, a bit lower performance
and no public IPs for any instances. I mean it's still going to work of course, it's just for a different sort
of requirements, horses for courses as we say here in the UK. This use case is going to be a bit more suited
for things like hosts that need access to the internet for let's say patches and software updates.
Anyway, this is what we're going to build. First up, we're going to spin up what's called a NAT instance
and we're going to spin it up in our public subnet. We'll use an Amazon provided AMI for that and although
it's just a Linux instance, it is a bit special. We're going to use it like a router.
So kind of a proxy middle man, right, where we send it packets and it in turn delivers those packets
to the internet. So we'll spin the instance up and then we'll configure it to disable source and
destination checks and this is vital, right. Because this is what lets it act like a router, receiving packets
from our private subnet and passing them onto the internet or the internet gateway, I should say.
Now, all instances have got this attribute called source and destination checks and by default it's set to enable,
and all that does, right, is say, hey anytime you receive a packet on the network, check it and see if it's
either from your or to you, if it's not, drop it. So don't pass it onto anyone else.
Well obviously that's not good behavior for a router whose raison d'être is obviously to forward packets on
that are not addressed to it. So we're going to need to disable that check.
Also, we're going to manually update the routing table in our private subnet so that it's got a default route
that throws packets to the NAT instance. This way, anything that's not matched by the local route
gets thrown over to the NAT instance, which then in turn is going to throw them over to the internet gateway,
which is then going to throw them onto, well the internet. Magic.
Now a couple of quick points before we go and configure it. This config of using a NAT instance here as a router
is going to act a bit like a stateful firewall of sorts, right. So, yes, while we can send traffic
out to the internet, the only traffic that's going to be allowed back in is going to be bona fide responses
to stuff we've already sent out. So, unsolicited incoming traffic, so stuff that's not in response
to something we've already sent, it's going to get dropped. In technical speak, that means our NAT instance
is going to allow stateful responses. Also, right, what's going on under the cover in the NAT instance
is actually PAT, port address translation, it's not NAT.
So remember how we said earlier that our instances in a public subnet, we assign each instance a publically
routable IP address and then the internet gateway maintains that mapping table between public and private IPs?
Well that can't be the case for this setup, right? Because the only instance that's part of this party,
with a public IP, is going to be the NAT instance itself. So we'll end up in a situation where we've got
multiple instances in our private subnet here all trying to get out to the internet via a single public IP
on the NAT. So what happens is the NAT instance, sure, it's got its own public IP to get to the internet,
but it maintains a mapping table that maps private IP addresses of instances on the private subnet
to its own public IP plus a unique port number. So let's say we've got two instances down here, right,
with a single private IP each. This particular one might be associated with port 6000 and then this one with
port 6001. So, any traffic that comes back to the NAT, so a bona fide response, as long as it comes back on
port 6000 it's going to get forwarded onto this instance. Okay, theory, theory, theory, should we actually
go and do it?