The name of the game when it comes to security is defense in-depth.
In tech, right, the idea being to deploy many and varied security technologies.
Oh man, wordles like that feel like so last year now, anyway, we deploy these different but complimentary techs
at different layers in the stack and different places in the network, like throwing multiple obstacles
in the way of potential intruders or attackers. The driving principle behind the whole thing being
there's no silver bullet when it comes to security, so no single uber product that on its own is going to keep
our apps and our data safe. And you know what too? Don't throw all of your eggs in one basket either.
So don't put your trust in not only a single product, but don't put your trust in any single vendor either.
Be wise. Well, we learned that when it comes to security of our VPCs,
Amazon provides a couple of important technologies, sort of out of the box, yeah, security groups and
network access control lists. So, network access control lists or NACLs as I've been calling them,
work at the subnet level, like firewalls for our subnets. So, they help protect everything inside of a subnet,
security groups, on the other hand, they work at the instance level, like personal firewalls for each of our
EC2 instances. And the two technologies totally complement each other, yeah, both allow us to control
the flow of inbound and outbound traffic, but they have got subtle differences, which if we understand
them can help provide a fairly decent defense. And you know what?
There's absolutely no harm in duplicating rules at both levels, so maybe having the same or very similar rules
at both the NACL and security group levels. In fact, you know what?
I recommend it. And as well, they can totally be complemented by third party products, so you might want to
design your subnets and the likes to mimic traditional enterprise grade corporate networks, so having
DMZs and the likes, yeah. And you know what? There's absolutely nothing stopping you throwing in software based
third party firewall and threat management products. You know what though?
The big takeaway point from the module, I hope, is that security is important and you definitely want to
invest the time and effort needed to secure your VPCs. Right,
now I reckon if you've been following along from the start, so watching the modules in order, you'll probably
up to speed no with the basics of operating VPCs. We've covered off the fundamentals and basic stuff pretty well.
Well, coming up next, we're going to start getting into what I consider the more advanced stuff
or the cool stuff, yeah. And we'll start that off with load balancing.