Okay, I think I'll take one more question. Yep. Hello governor, so when you think I should use public subnets
and when should I use private subnets? Okay, so this is a bit of a tricky one, I mean it's the kind of question
that deserves a, well that depends answer. But that sucks, right, and I'm hardly going to say that.
Though it is try, it really does depend. That all said though, I'd say a good general rule is to use
public subnets sparingly. Basically, right, anything you put in a public subnet has a route to the internet
and it's often going to have a public IP, and that combination is going to make it more open to attacks.
If you can, right, maybe try and rig things up so that you only stick like elastic load balancers,
firewall instances, proxy servers, that kind of stuff in public subnets.
Maybe web servers if you need to, yeah. Then, stick everything else into private subnets, where there's no
route to the internet and they don't have public IPs. I don't know if that's a good answer or not,
but I do reckon it's a pretty good rule of thumb, you won't go far wrong by sticking to it.
Alright then, thanks everyone for your time participating in the course.
Genuinely, genuinely do appreciate it.
Feel free to stick around for the quick summary and what's next module.