Okay, so from our EC2 console here, let's launch a new instance.
And we want Community AMIs here, then search for something with NAT in it.
This HVM bit here, just make sure that I don't get an old style pair of virtual instance, because
we want the full on hardware virtual machine version, right? And then 2015 just filters it so that I only see
recent versions. If you're watching this in 50 years, yeah, well, anyway we'll take this one here.
The difference being, right, this GP2 bit here, this is telling us that this one's going to be based on
super flashy SSD rather than magnetic rotating _____ for it's disk.
Anyway, micro is good for us. We want our podcast VPC up here and importantly, right, it's got to go
in the public subnet. Now if you stick it in the wrong subnet here, you might as well just destroy the thing
and build a new one from scratch because migrating instances between subnets is just, well I was going to say hard,
it's not actually that it's hard, it's just hmm, it's more manual than it should be.
Anyway, it needs to go in the public subnet, okay. And it definitely needs a public IP.
Right. Yep, general purpose SSD, that's good. And let's call it podcast-NAT.
Okay, we might as well configure the security groups while we're here.
So this SSH rule, that's going to be fine for now. In the real world, yeah, you're probably going to want to
lock the source bit down so that it just accepts connections from IPs on your management network or
something like that. But the thing is, right, the thing to do here is add rules for the type of traffic you
want to allow out. Well, we'll add a rule here for HTTP and then we'll add another one for HTTPS.
I don't know why they can't be together, but what we want to do is lock the source addresses down
to our private subnet so that only instances in the private subnet, right, are going to be allowed,
so that's going to be 10.0.2.0/24 and same again here (Typing). Next we want to, huh, outbound rules,
am I missing it? Okay I mean it's not often that I configure security groups from here, so I don't know,
maybe that's all you can do from here, maybe it's an old EC2 classic relic.
Yeah, I'm definitely not seeing a way to add outbound rules here.
Okay onwards and upwards. Oh, no, actually first up, let's give it a name (Typing).
And same again here, right, now let's go launch it (Typing). Okay, and let's find it.
Now to disable those source and destination checks. Networking, there it is.
Yep, we're sure, thank you. And I think we should be able to see it somewhere down here, yeah, there.
False, so disabled. Now to update the route table for our private subnet (Typing), I think this is the one,
yep, podcast-priv 1 here. So let's give it a new default route (Typing).
And the target, nice, we want this one, the NAT instance rather than the internet gateway.
And I reckon we're good. That's our private subnet all set up and ready.
So the instances that we launch in there can get out to the internet via the NAT proxy instance
that we put in the public subnet. Should we go wrap the module up?