Now then, while that instance spins itself up, okay, oh yeah right, here we go.
First up, see how we can tell which one's our new instance because we can see it's not fully up and running,
well we should totally have named our instance when we were creating it.
Slap across the chops for me for defying one of my very own golden rules, though shalt name all of thy AWS stuff.
I think we just skipped a place where we could have done that, but you can see I'm sure, right, that if we've got
a bunch of instances and we've not named them, we're going to have to do a bunch of digging around to work out
which instance is which, so let's name it now (Typing). Okay, now down here we can see its public IP.
Well I'm recording this course from a Windows machine, so I'm going to connect to it via SSH using PuTTY,
only PuTTY doesn't like the .PAM key format that AWS provides. So I'm going to fire up PuTTY Gen.
I'm going to import a key, this one's ours, and hit Save private key, and okay, no, we don't want to give it
a passphrase because that just adds an extra authentication step when we come to connect.
So let's save it (Typing), now let's open up PuTTY. Now first up, we need that public IP of our instance (Typing).
Right, then we want to tell PuTTY to use our private key that we just converted.
Now let's make the font as readable as we can without being ridiculous.
I think lastly we'll tell it what username to use when connecting.
Ubuntu is the default ofr Ubuntu instances. Well, I reckon we're good to go.
Boom. Look at that, we're in on a fully internet accessible, yep, fully internet accessible server.
Oh, and let's not forget in our world class data center. Not bad for a day's work, eh.
In fact not even that, a few minutes work. Oh man, we live in a great world these days.
I remember when something like this would have taken an age to build and cost an arm and a leg.
Well, as Hannibal from the A-Team used to say, I love it when a plan comes together.