Alright then, what did we cover in this module? Well I know this much, we spent a bunch more time on VPC
config than I expected at first. Never mind though. We kicked things off by building a new VPC again,
but this time without the help of the wizard. We called it podcast and we gave it a /16 CIDR block of addresses.
Now I know we said this as well, right, we said be careful when choosing the CIDR block because if you want to go
hook your VPC up to let's say your corporate network over a VPN at some time in the future or maybe you want to
create a pairing connection to another VPC, these are probably only going to work if the CIDR blocks
of the two networks don't overlap. So make sure they're not both, for instance, 10.0.0.0, I keep running out of
zeros here, 10, 3 zeros, /16. If they're both the same, you're going to have problems when you try and connect them.
And we also pointed out stuff like VPCs are per region, yeah. Yes, they span multiple availability zones,
but those availability zones all need to be in the same region.
We can't have a single VPC spanning multiple regions, at least not at the time of recording.
Then we covered off some of the VPC related options. DHCP options sets was one of them, right.
Now we said these are tied to our AWS account so we can attach them to any of our VPCs.
And they let us manage whether or not our instances will be able to, let's say, resolve DNS names to IP addresses,
and that there's not a kosher AWS style icon for DHCP options sets, right.
I'm not even sure they've got one. But there were some other options as well.
So we can use DHCP options sets to configure things like NTP servers, yes, and the DNS name suffix
that gets applied to our instance host names. Then after all of that, we finally got around to creating
a couple of subnets, just a nice little way of carving up our larger VPC network into smaller, more discrete,
and more manageable sub-networks. And like we just inferred a second ago, these exist within a single VPC,
so within a single region. But the important thing is, right, they are tied to a single availability zone
and that's important because subnets are a great way for us to pin services down to a particular availability zone.
So, want to spin up an instance or a service in a particular availability zone?
No worries. What we do is we spin it up in a subnet that's in that zone, dead simple.
So far though, we've just been slinging everything into a single subnet and a single availability zone.
But later on we'll definitely get into how we leverage subnets and availability zones to build high availability
into our apps. Anyway, then we looked at routers and route tables.
We said that every VPC automatically gets an implied router. Implied, implying, or suggesting it's just there.
We don't need to create it, indeed we can't create it nor can we delete it.
It really is just there. All we need to do is manage the route table entries that get associated
with each of our subnets. Remember we said these route tables are like the directions or the road signs
that point traffic down the different routes. So a route table, and you know, that one there on the screen
is not helping us at all. Yeah, this one's tons better. See, it even looks a bit like a road sign.
So, hey, I want to talk to a device with an address somewhere in this VPC, so on 10.0.0.0/16, hit the local route,
anything else, that's what the all zeros here means, go and use this igw router here instead.
And Amazon promises, those are my words actually not theirs, that this router is always going to be there
and that it's not going to be a bottle neck. Cool, okay, but on the flip side, it's pretty much invisible to us,
we've got zero insight into how it actually works or how it's performing.
We've just got to trust Amazon and that's a sticky point for a lot of people.
I mean I don't even like it personally, but it's just the way it is.
What else did we say? Oh yeah, we said every VPC has got a main route table, which is just like a default
route table for that VPC. We can tweak it if we want and we can even change which table is the main table.
So we do have some choices there. But you know what? I reckon that's pretty much the bulk of what we learned.
Next up, we're going to take what we've learned about routing here and hook our public subnet up to the internet
as well as a bunch more cool stuff. But for me, right, this is where I think it really starts getting interesting.