Alright then, so let's draw a picture of what we've learned. So starting out from a base of a VPC
and a couple of subnets in a single availability zone, first up we created an internet gateway,
effectively a router with an interface into our VPC and another one facing the internet.
And it only took like a couple of clicks to create, thanks for that Amazon.
But don't let that fool you. Remember, this beast scales like a reptile and it promises to still be standing
as the sun turns supernova. So it's pretty decent and no need for us to sweat over its performance or its
availability characteristics, assuming you trust Amazon, of course.
Anyway the fact is it gives us a reliable way out to the internet.
Then we updated the route table associated with our public subnet so that it knew about the internet gateway, yeah,
we used 0.0.0.0/0 plus the internet gateway as a default route for the subnet.
So the route to take when nothing else matches what you want. Then after that we saw how to assign public IPs
to instances, either manually when launching the instance or by setting the auto-assign public IP property
of the subnet. But don't forget, you don't own those types of public addresses, so they don't stick around
after reboot, making them no good for any time where you might need a persistent IP address that maybe
you publish to your clients and the likes. For reliable IPs that you do own and that you pay for
when they're not in use, you want to go with elastic IPs. These are still full of public routable goodness,
but they belong to you so they're not going to bail out on you when the goes gets tough.
And that pretty there is public subnets in the internet. So after we were done with that, we switched our attention
to our private subnet and we gave it the gift of internet access, but through a proxy host in the form of NAT instance
that we stuck in the public subnet. This is just like a Linux instance, right, that forwards packets
onto the internet for us and it wasn't even hard to build. We grabbed one from the community marketplace.
Sure we have to disable source and destination checks and we added a default route to the route table
in the private subnet, so an entry that sent all unmatched traffic over to the NAT instance, but that wasn't hard.
You know what? I reckon that's pretty much what we did in this module.
Cracking stuff, right? I mean, that diagram is starting to look pretty decent now, don't you think?
Almost like a real data center. Oh I'm not kidding, this is good stuff now.
None of this old EC2 classic style stuff where we had no control over networking and the likes, no way,
this is proper good stuff that we're building here. Anyway, next on the fight card
is security groups and network access control lists, more good stuff.
What we're about to do is start building a solid layered security model to give us even better control
of our infrastructure. You're not going to want to miss that.