Okay, so let's recap what I think are the main highlights of what we've achieved here.
So we pretty much started out with this, yeah, that's right, a blank sheet of paper.
No infrastructure to run our apps on. Then purely by having an AWS account, boom,
we instantly got a whole bunch of this kind of stuff behind us and what that is is world class data center
infrastructure and we could start building on it and thanks to Amazon all of that physical stuff
is their problem now. We don't have to care about it anymore, well, okay that's not exactly true,
we still need to care of course, we just don't need to have it up front and central on our personal to do lists,
which no doubt are already long enough as it is. Thanks to Amazon we just care about the compute network
and storage that our apps run on. So, we went from this
and we started off by building a VPC, which is like the logical boundary of the virtual private cloud
or the virtual private data center that we were going to build in AWS.
You know what? It's not too dissimilar to leasing an empty hole in a colo data center, all the AC, the power,
all of that shenanigans is taken care of by someone else, in our case Amazon.
Anyway, we gave that VPC a network and a name, then we carved that network into two subnets.
We made one of them public and the other one private and we pretty much said, right, the only difference
is the existence of a route from the public subnet to the internet via an internet gateway.
Then, we spun up an instance in the public subnet and we made sure that it got assigned a public IP address.
Then we initiated an inbound SSH connection to the instance using that public IP.
It's just insane, honestly it is. With a few clicks of a mouse and a pathetically small incursion on our
credit card, we've effectively built a data center. But we've bought or leased no land.
We've built or leased no building, put up no security perimeter, connected no power, connected no
Telco communications, we've racked no servers, ran no cables, nothing.
Amazon has done it all for us. All we had to do was to find a few networks and even that was a walk in the park.
Internet gateways were built for us, network routes were configured, access control lists, so much stuff,
and we never even broke a sweat. Anyone watching fancy going back to the old days where something like this
would have taken months of hard labor and negotiations, not to mention a boat load of up front capital?
Not me. Welcome to the future, it's bright and it's in the cloud.
But, and there's always a but, right, I want to give a big old warning here.
You might be tempted to think, hey now I can go and build a private data center in Amazon and the world
is my oyster and yeah it is, but don't go running straight off and deploying your apps into what we just built there.
There's actually a ton more that you're going to want to learn before you start hosting your prime time on Amazon.
And I'm not just talking fancy stuff like high availability and auto-scaling, I'm talking critical
fundamental stuff like making sure that public IP just gave to you instance doesn't change when you reboot
your instance because the way that we built the VPC in this module here, as soon as you reboot that instance,
it's going to lose that public IP and get a shiny new one. And I'm sure you grock, that is far from ideal
when you just told a paying customer that it was going to be the IP address of an API endpoint or something like that.
So stick around, there's plenty more still to learn.
Coming on up in the next module, we're going to start from scratch again and we're going to build a VPC
by hand, no, that's not right actually, it's still going to be pointing and clicking, right.
What I mean is we're going to build it manually, so no wizard this time.
Wizards are for wimps anyway, you never learn anything using a wizard.
So meet me back here when I've cleaned things down and we'll start building a VPC manually and learning
how it's all strung together under the hood, sound good? Right, see you there.